you have this device and you want to
take which has its own tool chain which
has its own like operating system
whatever you take this architecture
everything right everything like and
it's not like using the word saying
everything on it is living in an Harmony
together it's just some sort of a [__]
glue together which is like some sort of
abomination that they've managed to like
just make it work and then you just want
to take like one piece of that
comination and put it on the latest
Linux version on your server of course
it's not going to work right of
[Music]
course hey guys real quick I just wanted
to tell you about our sponsor threat
Locker now wait wait before you hit the
skip forward button let me just say this
most of the stuff that holds my
attention nowadays is red team stuff as
well but I sat down with the threat
Locker team this past week to do a demo
of their EDR software and it was super
technically fascinating how this thing
works so check this out you drop this
thing on a system right and for the
first week or so it's creating a policy
and a profile for that system it's
logging all the executables uh what
child processes are being spawned uh the
files and their hashes that sort of
thing and it's creating this policy okay
then after the learning mode is up we're
in secured mode and that policy gets put
into place and anything that's not on
that allow list is immediately autod
denied that's the zero trust piece right
so in addition to that they've got a
bunch of crazy features like ring
fencing and dynamic access controls that
would stop a malicious hacker at pretty
much every step along the way actually I
I was watching this demo and I was kind
of freaked out because I have no idea
how I would cope with getting dropped
into a threat locker system as a red
teamer anyway if you want to learn more
about this head over to at locker.com
and request a demo and when you do ask
for my boy Andrew his demo was super to
the point and he was able to answer all
my technical questions all right cool
back to the
show all righty dude I am hyped for this
episode I have wanted to do a an episode
with someone from pone toone since the
beginning of this podcast and finally
we're having it happen so uh Cena thanks
so much for coming on the Pod
man thanks for having me man I
appreciate that I'm so delighted to be
here and I really don't know why you
chose me to be here well here you've
been cranking out content like crazy
lately and your bugs are are amazing so
I'm sure I'm sure we'll we'll get into
that a little bit as we go into the Pod
but um dude I have to I have to
compliment this setup before we get
rolling homies got the DSLR inl and you
got like the Hat behind you and like
it's it's looking fly man thanks for
putting all that effort into it thank
you uh yeah I do a lot of uh photography
and like uh Productions and different
kind of stuff and uh yeah I sometimes
use a save camera for these kind of cool
meetings that we have such as this one
and yeah this this is actually hat from
ponon oh nice got it from there and I've
had it signed by I don't know if it's if
you can see it but I've had it signed by
Dustin Charles oh really nice he's a
he's a legend there he works at um Tren
micro Z the initiative uh he's the head
of TR burus if I'm not wrong nice nice I
actually I actually reached out to him
when I was trying to Source people for
this episode and I was like hey man I
see that you kind of run Pon to own um
who would you recommend for this episode
and and he gave me a couple names and
you you were on that list and I was like
all right this is my man after I did a
little bit of research into it so um
shout out to Dustin as well for for
setting that up um all right dude so
let's let's spend some time okay so let
me let me give a little context here so
um I am
a I'm someone who participates often in
the in the hacker one live hacking event
scene and you are someone that
participates often in the pone to own
scene right and I kind of wanted to do
an episode where we discuss the
differences of these two these two
worlds of bug Bounty right because I
feel like there's the hacker one bug
crowd Integrity that sort of group and
then there's like the Ponto own zdi
group um and we don't see a lot of
overlap from them oddly enough um and
and I think there there is some reason
for that I think some of the um some of
the skill sets are a little bit
different um especially with with uh
ponon and zdi primarily focusing on rce
as a as a vul class you know poning
poning as you would say a specific
Target um but so I'm excited to kind of
uh iron out the differences between
hacker one related live hacking events
and pone to own related stuff um but I
also before we jump into all that I want
to hear a little bit about you and how
you got into hacking and how you ended
up at the pon tone
competitions I appreciate it uh so first
of all let me just start saying English
is not my first language so if I kind of
like do like a stutter or anything yeah
I hope people forgive me about that uh
I'm trying my best kind of yeah and
uh yeah so uh about uh um giving like a
brief introduction about myself I'm a
full-time vulnerability researcher I've
been for the last uh I don't know how
many years now uh and uh when I started
uh I've actually started as a developer
I was making commercial websites with my
brother when I was a kid and then uh he
he kind of taught me like web
development basic stuff and then we were
just making websites and then uh finding
customers to sell them e-commerce
websites very very simple stuff back in
the day and then uh actually one of my
websites one day got hacked and then I
it got defaced um was this a bigger
customer was this a small site or like
what was
the uh it was it was a small customer
and then but but the problem was so so
back in the day I wouldn't be I don't
think people even do it nowadays but uh
I would just like make like I don't know
five five back ends and I've just
changed the front ends for different
customers because it was it was
e-commerce website right you have the
shopping cart you have check out all of
that stuff it's kind of the logic is the
same right and so I just exactly the
very very common components it it would
be like five different back ends and
then the front ends would be like
hundreds of different kind of front ends
um and uh yeah one day one of my
websites got hacked and then they would
keep getting hacked like the guy kind of
like d dorked on Google or something and
then it was just like finding all of
them and then just like blasting all of
them and then just defacing them and
then just submitting sub submitting them
to these like kind of like uh you know
defacing websites back from back in the
day Maybe not maybe let's not name them
but anyways um yeah they they were just
submiting them and um I don't know um
get didn't reput
and just it was just defacing them and
then uh when I saw it initially I was
like wow it was the first time that I
was like seeing Stu that I made was
being hacked and then I was I was like
so surprised by it and then I thought it
over and I was like let's let's actually
reach out to the guy because he defaced
the website and then he left out his
like email address like down the page
saying like I don't know hacked by like
this this kind of like a cool hacker
handle and then uh some sort of a
country flag was on it too as well some
like blood dripping from the page you
know like all this stuff very dramatic
to face and then
he exactly and then uh he had his email
address there and then I I reached out
to him and I app he said hey I made the
website I'm the de behind it I do this
for the living and I was wondering if
you can give me some pointers on how you
did it so I can prevent it from
happening again so I can keep selling my
stuff and then the guy replied back to
me I think after two days saying he was
like I like your I like your initiative
and that you reached out to have the
problem solved in some sort of way so he
was like maybe impressed or something
and then he wrote back to me uh exactly
with what the problem was and he was
using all of these like complicated
terminologies which back in the day I
didn't kind of understand like things
like oh like you had a SQL injection
here and then after I exploited your SQL
injection um I was able to um oh the
user that was your website was run being
running on uh was like a myql user with
like root privileges and I was able to
like write to a file or something and
then after I WR to a file and then I
managed to like visit the file and then
get code execution with my webshell and
then uh the the webshell from the old
school back in the day the ones that
existed back back in the time um and
then yeah he he did it that way and then
he was uh he he was giving me my code
Snippets back like marking them exactly
where the bug was right right wow which
was
crazy yeah um and uh and then I realized
how how far he was able to go uh when
just through like uh from like an
initial book to another book to another
book but I didn't understand like chains
or whatever back in the day um and then
I was so like fascinated by like the
things that he did um I've told him that
uh I'm so grateful for for the all the
explanation that you did I'm actually so
interested in this I I will try to
pursue it to to to make my website
better and then it kind of like clicked
from that way to uh doing like a lot of
searches there there wasn't any kind of
like a lot of resources whatever you had
like these I don't know like a Chinese
forums or Russian Forum or like a I
don't know
Forum was this like you know early 2000s
or like when was this uh this is uh yeah
yeah something like that something like
that exactly something like not a lot of
stuff out there for that at that time to
learn how to
hack it was again way more than like
something from the 90s maybe like way
more but um no you didn't have like
payload all things or like something
that it was like a centralized place
that had you had all the links to the to
the latest techniques and tools and
tricks and bypasses and mitigations you
didn't have people dropping bypasses on
Twitter that much as they do now every
day there's like a new bypass right um
and I was I was actually very interested
in it and then i' I've started like
searching and searching and searching
and uh translating I had like this
Babylon I don't know if I'm pronouncing
it right or wrong this like babyon
translator on my on my desktop who just
like copy paste stuff to it and then
just try to understand like different
kind of languages what they were meaning
and then um yeah basically uh I've got
it from there and then I was so
interested in that uh I've I've started
like pursuing it and uh going after it
and then trying to learn more and more
and more and then shout out to one guy
who who actually like played like a key
role in my in my learning curve um he PE
people don't know him that that much
because uh he's not he's not like
globally well known like he's not I
don't I don't think even he is on
Twitter or something his his name is mam
he mam monf uh he was he was a teacher
of mine back in the day that uh taught
me a lot of about web development
security he was like one of these like
old school hack hackers who like learned
everything by himself like he he he was
from the like he was from the 80s or
like 90s something and then everything
by himself like uh and he was this like
still to this day he's he was like a
legend to me back in the day and he had
like played like a very very key role in
my learning path and U teaching me a lot
of things he helped me to build like a
strong foundation in um algorithm and
understanding like coding and everything
not just copy pasting and like just like
um like he he built like a really good
foundation for me and then sking that
Kitty stuff yeah
exactly like he like I can't tell you
how much of a strong Foundation he had
he had even a still to this day I'm sure
uh and uh that that like taught me a lot
about if you understand the architecture
actually instead of just copy pasting
payos and just just getting your way if
you understand how actually things work
that takes you like a lot of extra mild
um absolutely and and and I think so I
think it's really interesting that you
started out from webdev and then you
went to web hacking right and and I
think that's a pretty traditional flow
for the the people in in the hacker one
scene as well is like you now we're
focusing on these these web bugs and and
like idor and access control related
stuff right but then you know instead of
going down this path of like oh let me
identify all these web bugs and and do
web related stuff quite as much you end
up somehow in the the you know binary
exploitation scene as well um so what
was that what was that progression like
uh as a hacker like when did you start
switching from all right I'm finding
sqls in in PHP code to all right let me
load this thing up in in gidra or
whatever and and start reverse
engineering
it uh that's actually a great question
so exactly back in the day at that time
that I started like working on web stuff
um that the same guy the same guy that I
knew he was actually an expert in like
lowlevel exploitation uh like uh um and
he he was very good at it uh like he was
like this like cc++ Guru and then he was
able to like craft exploit for like
kernel drivers and everything and he was
he was just like just genius and then uh
we were actually so we didn't have
access to like Ida and gidra wasn't a
thing back there and like lot of this
assemblers that you see nowadays one the
thing so we were just like using like
all the dbg if I'm pronouncing the name
right so it was this is it's like one of
these like you know like one of these
like really ancient uh powerful very
very very powerful debuggers that I
still see to the state people use so he
told me he told me that um listen like
you can use this like tool and um I
don't have time he he didn't he didn't
have lot of time at his hand he wasn't
like a personal tutor or something was
just a it was like more like a friend uh
and then he kind of like encouraged me
to go learn like a sbly and he was he
was very like um he was very strict with
foundation so he wasn't like okay you
just open this up you just drag and drop
something here you look for this and
that and click click click done or like
copy paste stuff he was he was very
strict with building a strong foundation
and then uh that's why i' i' I've went
out and then like started like buying
books and stuff about like learning
assembly like hello V uh we had like a
some sort of like a local hacker Meetup
kind of thing back in the day that uh
yeah yeah exactly and then I was trying
to like connect with people to to learn
from them and stuff and then I didn't I
didn't end up making any friends but I
did end up meeting this guy and then the
way that I met this guy was actually
through like initially I thought he's
just a web dev guy uh but he was way
more to to what I thought he was uh he
he he was he was he was super humble
super humble uh super humble guy that he
didn't just start like blabbering about
okay I know this I'm like the Jack of
all tra or whatever he was actually like
he was actually
very like he was a ninja like he he a
still to this day like and and he and he
was he was also a great teacher which uh
which not everybody can teach you can be
great at what you do but that's a rare
overlap you know if you can if you have
the ability to to especially be a jack
of all traits have such a a high amount
of knowledge and then be able to teach
and then furthermore to be able to teach
in such a way that you give the the
student the right foundation and allow
them to almost learn for themselves
teach them how to learn um how to get
you know some of these skills along the
way so that's man what what a what a
blessing this guy was to you and it
seems like he was really key in your
development exactly yeah he he was like
a he he was like a high booster for me
um in uh if I am anything today uh I
haven't reached much today but uh if I
like reached anything like that you can
like count it uh it it goes back to the
roots of uh meeting with him and uh
basically yeah he encouraged me like
building the foundation and then uh
after like started like reading about
like exactly at the so at the same time
so I I would like divide my day to doing
like okay I'm going to do I'm going to
do web stuff I'm going to learn about
like SQL injection like I don't know
like uh I don't know local file
inclusion remote file inclusion this
this and that and then serialization and
whatever back in the day and then I
would I would be also doing uh
dedicating some like uh three four hours
to reverse engineering building building
up the foundation like learning uh
learning assembly and learning all that
and then there wasn't again there wasn't
much resources but the ones that were
available were were actually good enough
and um um and you know like at least for
me
uh I think it was pretty important that
things were more difficult back in the
day and that kind of helped me to to
struggle more and to try more uh so
nowadays when I nowadays that things are
I think pretty much I I think it kind of
I don't want to exactly it's more
developed right maybe maybe using the
word easier will will like offend
someone not easier but it's like more
accessible to people absolutely uh yeah
and then that that that helps more into
like finishing something um and then I
think not having a lot of available
things uh as much as today compared to
back then uh it kind of helping uh like
developing that kind of like intuition
to not give up and then just just keep
trying and keep trying and keep studying
and keep studying and keep studying
without thinking that when does it get
over because it never gets over exactly
it's just endless that's that's one of
the things I always tell to the students
that I work with is like listen um you
know you can read all these tutorials
and you can go out there and and like
you said a lot of the content is made
really accessible nowadays um but the
real learning is going to occur when you
get out there and you fail and you fail
and you fail and you fail and you fail
and you fail you know but but there's
there's a finite number of failures
between you know now and the next time
that you pop a crazy bug right and so
you just got to get out there and start
knocking those out of the way um because
experience is going to be the best
teacher in a lot of these scenarios you
know you see some of these newer guys
just looking at hdp request and they're
like man I I have no idea what all of
these headers mean you know and I'm like
all right well just look it up real
quick you know and you you got to pay
the price to know you know what these
things are and then once you started
knocking them out once you started doing
some reps on it
um you know you'll sort of get a sense
for what's interesting and what's not
interesting um and I think it's we've
kind of inversely switched into a
different problem now which I see a lot
of a lot of people fall into which is um
what we call education procrastination
which is you're just constantly learning
reading reading learning learning and
you never get to the actual doing part
um and and I think it's it's so
important for beginners to get out there
even if you don't feel like you know
what you're doing even if you're just
stabbing in the dark to just get out
there and fail and have that be a key
part of your your education
process um I don't want to I don't want
to sound like a guy who who's just going
to say exactly yes I I agree with that
but but here speaking facts so exactly I
I I agree with that and
then as corny as it sounds like when
when you tell people nowadays to try
harder go at it like as you said do the
Reps or like fail and fail and fail and
all that sounds like all of these like
because nowadays there's like all of
these motivational videos or like people
trying to like sell you a course to how
to how to become a billionaire and using
the same actual sentences as we are
saying right here it might kind of like
cancel out in some people's mind that
okay we're just trying to make it make
it sound difficult even though it isn't
but it it like if if you want to do like
cool [__] like you got to you got to do
the Reps you got to you know you you got
to you got to build it right you got to
fail and fail and fail and debug and
debug and debug and then just like these
muscles right devop
that yeah I think you got to start
another separate channel for uh
bodybuilding
body well I I know you said you you hit
the gym right before this episode so
maybe you and I we'll do a uh you know a
gym episode in Vegas or something like
that all right so yeah you said you know
okay so you you met this guy and he and
he really helped you with a foundation
of okay so we're working on SQL
injection and then we're switching over
to you know reverse engineering for a
couple hours and we're really kind of
getting a great Foundation um in place
and and so I'm I'm curious you know as
this Foundation starts going in in in in
place one how are you feeling as you're
building all this right because you're
not actively out there like popping
exploits and stuff like that you're
you're building a lot of this foundation
so are you feeling an or you just kind
of like you're like uh maybe this isn't
the right path or you are you kind of
trusting that this is the right path and
uh just kind of being really interested
in the stuff that you're learning at the
time um at uh this this is a question
for at the time right back in the day
right as I was doing it yeah
so I didn't have any perspective of what
I'm going to do like I I didn't think
there would be a job even there's like a
cyber security job a vulnerability
nothing I was just
I just wanted to get like shells just
wanted to get sh just wanted to like get
the get the rush when you exploit
something and that and also the pause
between these rushes that you're
spending time to find the bug so that
pause kind of like would build that
expectation and then when you like
satisfy the expectation of okay I I hit
it now I've I've got a shell I popped
the Cal I popped Ms paint whatever like
I I just wanted to do it I I didn't have
any idea like it's addicting and then at
a time um so one one might ask like okay
then how would you were like making a
living like you couldn't just like stay
at home and just do this so I I had like
my developer geek and then I was just
like uh try to like make money out of
that and then I tell you like like 247
like 247 like uh I would just get to get
the get like the client project done or
whatever and the good thing with the
development jobs like I as I told you
like you had like I don't know like 10
back back ends and you just like change
the front ends whatever and then
sometimes like minor modifications in
order to like sell that kind of like a
CMS or whatever the product you had at
the time and then yeah I was just like
being like my my whole word like was
just that just to reverse engineer or do
source code review and just find box and
I would just go on like any kind of like
a website that would say okay this is a
trial of our product this is a demo of
this like open source close Source
whatever just take it just test out
everything like fail and fail and just
go go into this like different rabbit
holes and I I literally didn't like I
kid you not like I would just install
the software and i' be like okay what am
I going to do next okay what what am I
even going look at attack surface attack
surface was a joke I didn't know what an
attack surface was I couldn't even like
like I would just install it and i' be
like okay I I'm just going to interact
with this thing and then understand [__]
can go wrong at at a certain point just
like just like that right and then um as
I was doing this and then just reading
and reading and reading and all of that
and kind of like you know it goes kind
of like those like you know it's like
the classic classic story of background
story of everyone else like they started
from somewhere they they they did they
did their time they they paid their I
don't know pay their dues or whatever
and then after a while they exactly and
then uh they build it up I did decided
and then uh and then after a point like
your skills just get sharper and sharper
at the time and then um yeah I remember
like uh I tell you like it was it was
24/7 like I would just like work until
like 12: or 1 p.m. and I would just
asleep until like 6 7 and I would just
wake up same screen same screen just
just looking at just like reversing
testing it right I mean I I think one of
the common themes that we see is is you
know in the beginning you didn't know
that this was a job right and I think
that's one of yeah I love bug Bounty
like bug Bounty is is one of the most
amazing things in my life for sure but I
do think that there's been a con Tob
Bounty a little bit which is people
focus on the Bounty right PE people
focus on my delimiter for success with
learning hacking is whether or not I'm
getting bounties or not and that's not
how it's supposed to be right H you need
to love hacking you need to love the
process of growing and hacking you need
to love the process of um you know
seeing this piece of software and just
like understanding how it works and
understanding its little nuances that
you can you know that you can break that
and and not to say that people can't
just do bug Bounty as a job people can
do bug Bounty as a job and if you're not
super mega passionate about it I'm not
trying to like gatekeep bug Bounty from
you but um I think to to to get to this
level where you're like finding super
crazy stuff and you're and you're um
just absolutely loving your job like
there has to be that focus on hacking as
a as a passion first
and then you're like oh wait you know
this is a this can be a job too um so I
always tell try to tell people to
release that whole expectation of bounty
in the beginning and just more focus on
like hacking as an art and as a craft
right you got a point there and let's
say let me also mention this right
so at the time when I was doing it and
lot of other people um the the the whole
thing was like a a dark path that you
didn't know where you're going and uh
like you didn't have like a centralized
place with all the attack surfaces and
all the attack lists and all the kind of
like the what's available or whatever it
was kind of like a dark path when just
like going and then you try to like
light up the whole like different alleys
and different like the streets and
whatever on this path just just slowly
but nowadays I don't know if what what's
it called in like what's what's the
right term but it's like uh when you
have a huge amount of information
available now and then when you want to
start you kind of get shocked right you
get scared you're like there is so much
to learn you're like so exactly you get
overloaded you're like oh my God like I
don't know if I I don't know if I want
to start this because it's too much like
how am I supposed to like learn all of
this but um which which which adds a
different kind of difficulty to to to
today's people that like are starting it
or have started it right uh back in the
day different problems now different
problems right and then you have a lot
of competitors and like uh different
kind of stuff adds up adds up to it as
well uh I think you just like just start
right just like just keep doing it just
just learn as you go just just learn
don't think about all the possib like
all the what's available just just try
to learn it slowly like building it just
like Go Go With It Go with like a normal
past and going and going and just like
build it up and um don't get don't get
distracted a lot and then I don't know I
don't know how to put it I I think at a
certain point I'm just keep repeating
myself well I I I think I think I think
you're repeating yourself because this
is a part of the process you know is is
just going down that pathway and and
like you said figuring out as you go um
and I love that you acknowledged that
there's difficulties to modern day
education in Buck Bounty too because I
think that's a really fair assessment of
it is that you know back in the day we
had too little information but now we've
got too much information and it's hard
to balance those two right um and and so
the the only way to balance those two is
get out there and do it um and so that's
why I always talk about you know I've
got pinned to my Twitter profile sort of
like a um uh a blueprint for how to get
started in bug Bounty and essentially
what I say is in the beginning you know
do 80% learning 20% hacking you know and
then you move up to 60% learning 40%
hacking and then it's 60% hacking 40%
learning right and but notice how
there's always some hacking involved in
there you know like um you have to be
out there actually doing the hacking um
for you to get reps so I think that's
really I think that's really important
um so okay so that's a little bit of
your of your background you you kind of
started with this really rigorous um you
know training and you were doing it for
the for the passion of it um and you
didn't even know that this could turn
into a job um but so when did that that
web development scale out and when did
you start working as a as a uh you know
as an offensive security expert or
vulnerability
research yep so so uh I was just like uh
doing this like uh just doing it for
myself just like trying to exploit stuff
and just like having my exploit python
files in my like local local drive and
just like looking at them and feeling
like I I like I roll the world or
whatever just like just just just
getting high on that and then uh after
after like going again and again and
again just like for exploring different
kind of stuff uh at a certain point I
was like hearing interacting with the
kind of like other people and then like
hearing about okay like there's a thing
like cyber security roles like Penta
roles and all of that so it wasn't like
vulnerability researcher or whatever
back just we had only one title back in
the day pentester are you a penter or
not that's it um yeah so I started like
as like a pend um and then just like
normal stuff like I don't know attacking
active directory um different kind of
like attacking active directory Network
scanning uh like vulnerability scanning
different kind of tools this and that
and that and then just like what what
like usual people do nothing nothing
fancy just like but I always try to like
do like that extra M I would just like
bring uh even though I don't recommend
it to people like this this doesn't
sound this this doesn't sound right to
people and people just prohibits doing
the prohibits doing this but I did it
back in the time because I didn't do it
for the companies that I work for I just
did it for myself I just like bring work
home and just trying to go that extra
mile to like find something fascinating
or find something interesting if if it
was just like a network pentest maybe I
can find some sort of a custom software
that I could like find like a heap
overflow in it and then I just like
craft an exploit for it how hard could
it be it's a Windows XP it's not like a
Windows 11 or whatever which is like all
the mitigations or you
like even there's there's ways to this
but it was way easier right I was just
try to like go that extra mile to try to
apply my I I would would make [__] up
like I would like make targets up like
my boss would have told me okay just
test this this software and that
software and that software that's that's
what we're being paid for right uh you
can test these as well but we're not
getting paid for I was like okay I want
to test those as well I'll just bring it
home I was just like work on them and
work on them and all that and then
that's great yeah I mean that that was
sort of the same same sort of thing that
I had which was like okay first you get
in that pentester role right and then
the next step is like master master that
and and like get it so that you can get
very satisfactory results um quickly you
know let's say it's a 40-hour test
you're you're popping everything and
getting it done in like 20 hours right
and then that extra 20 hours you've got
is like additional value add to the
client okay and by the way here's a zero
day in this Library you're using or like
you know here's that's that's perfect
man and that that's exactly what what I
did as well I think that's a really good
takeaway is like um you know go for
these go the extra mile on these
engagements but I think a lot of people
try to skip that first step which is
first Master what you're what you're
supposed to do you know master that that
that um initial pentest where you can
get the results you know that you need
for the client quickly and then you've
got that margin either at work or like
you said at home um to go the extra mile
and and and you know build out these
extra exploits and and apply the
knowledge that you you're getting
through your own study to these targets
that you're working on um that's that's
awesome man Okay cool so that so then
you you know you're in that pentesting
environment you're growing you're
growing and then do you stay as a
pentester long term or are you switching
into vulnerability research and and
where does pon to own fit into this
whole equation yeah uh so I was just
like doing like this pent RS and then
just like going through rank like a
junior senior medor whatever right just
going up and then um and then uh I at
the same time that I was like learning
all of these like Buck Bounty was being
like Pro promoted a lot and all that and
people were getting more into bu bound
even though there were people doing it
way back like people were doing it like
exactly the same day like hacker one was
launched and then like people were doing
it like all that but it was getting like
more promoted and like all that and then
um I've kind of I I kind of started
trying it and then I wasn't good at it
um I did I did make some money I I'm
like I I did some make money I did did
make some money and then like I was just
like targeting different kind of things
and and then the good thing I to be
honest um maybe maybe if I would have
like pursue it back then like it would
have been better instead of like giving
up on it because people were there
wasn't much automation back there as
today so so if if you were clever enough
to make some sort of automation back in
a day you would be like drowning in
money and uh but I I kind of like I I
didn't like I didn't click with with the
whole concept I wasn't probably because
I wasn't like much good at it but I did
make some money I was like reporting to
Microsoft and all that and then uh which
which was good I was like making good
money Microsoft was paying Microsoft uh
was paying a lot of money back in the
day I think compared to today maybe I
don't know uh but what happened was uh
to answer your question one day as I
would like any other day that I was just
like watch five or six conference videos
from different kind of things that would
come up to to try to like find my own
Niche or whatever I I saw a video of in
hack in the Box conference um from
stepen cely I think you know him uh I
saw yeah I saw one of his talks and um
when I saw it like he it was like so
fascinating to me I was like I've got to
do exactly what this guy does and I've
like started like Googling his name
reading whatever he wrote and then get
familiar with his blog and all of that
reading all of his explor and all of
that and then one thing that I
was one thing that I learned as I was
like doing all of this stuff was trying
to reproduce other people's
work I can't stress how important it is
today even though not even even though
not even even it's easier today today to
do it but I don't think much people are
doing it like you have like Docker
images that people will set up 10
minutes after the CV comes up you can
just do like a docker and then you have
the already vulnerable image set up P
exposed you have a sample of the payload
and you can just like fire it and test
it right and then people like start like
making all like nuclei stuff and like
just like spread through the whole
internet or whatever right and lot of
other stuff that I'm I'm not aware of
right that's just the thing that I know
uh but back in the day right people just
like publish the exploit and then uh
people weren't doing like nday analysis
and all of that but and no to be honest
nobody told me to do it I was just I was
just thinking okay I want to do exactly
what a Steven silly does right I I want
to get to his level even though he's
like way way
farther like that I can even look at
right he's just like on like this whole
like a different mountain and then I was
like okay okay maybe the best thing is
if I read these blogs and I don't
understand it I will just write down
everything that I don't understand even
from a simple word that says I don't
know something like a I don't know
whatever just write it down and then
just like start it start like slowly
building up my Foundation to understand
these blocks and then let's let's
install the same software let's try to
find same bug let's let's just try to do
the same thing as he did and keep
failing at it and just keep doing it and
keep doing it I've tried to reproduce as
much advisories and exploits that he had
published uh and then and then I've kind
of like I was I was feeling that I'm
stepping in the same shoe as he has is I
was just like stepping in the same shoe
and then I I've I've I've started like
developing that kind of like intuition
like just like close not exactly just
close like just trying to like be like
him right a a
well-known a well-known like experience
experienced expert vulnerability
researcher who who Who's a who has done
you anything you could think of like
back in the day he was like making
making he Heap exploitation plugins to
do like craziest stuff so he's not just
like this like highle guy who's only
doing like this kind of like one area he
he has done it everything you can think
of he has done like lowlevel
exploitation Hardware embedded high
level of stuff like exotic architecture
whatever you could think of right he has
done it like the like he he he became
and he is still to this day my role
model even even on even on my blog if
you go there like there's like about
page on top I put his name saying like
this this is one of the guys who had
like direct uh direct like impact on
what I am today even if I am anything
today but um yeah basically uh I've kind
of like started following his path just
going after what he did and all all the
things that I just I just said before
and then that's really great dude
because I think I think um you know F
when you see somebody like that and
they're inspiring you know you it's easy
to be like yeah I want to be like that
and then like just think about get sort
of fixated on the end goal like wouldn't
it be cool if I was like you know a
vulnerability researcher if I like did
this for a career or whatever and then
instead of focusing on that end goal you
start reverse engineering it you say
like okay well in order to get to where
he was he did all these bugs so I'm
going to go back and you know try to
reproduce all these bugs and you know
make it so that I could have found these
um so I like how you reverse engineered
uh you know Steven ceely as well that's
great you know uh you apply that reverse
engineering stuff to your You Know Your
Role Model there in that capacity as
well um and that's that's that's great
um so I guess where I want to go from
here is I want to talk about uh I want
to do one more section in the uh you
know about you area and talk about your
favorite bugs and and how those have
evolved over the years as you've you
know gained more capabilities and then I
kind of want to move into uh your
hacking methodology specifically and how
you've been popping all the these bugs
um on all these targets nowadays for
forone to own and um and and even
outside of that um and it's very source
code analysis heavy uh so I'm excited to
talk about that as well so start with
what are your favorite bugs that you
find a lot and then kind of move into
your hacking
methodology uh nowadays that the more
stuff that I find that are like more
interesting to me are more more like
memory corruption kind of stuff either
it's like a well like a kernel driver
mostly like Linux based or is it is it
like embedded device or like a something
else right more memory corruption
oriented kind of stuff are like uh like
my like top favorite kind of stuff to do
and uh I also like what but the things
that I'm that I'm allowed or able to
blog about is mostly like the high level
stuff that I find which are like either
deserialization path traversal you know
like your your simple stuff like
non-memory corruption kind of stuff any
everything that all the other people are
finding I'll just I just love to explain
uh code and just go through that um and
just like build it up from there and uh
it's it's exactly like uh projecting the
way um at least I'm trying to I'm
basically copying um that's why I'm
saying like maybe projecting is not a
right word but the the work that Steven
has been doing over years and years puts
like the source code exactly he puts on
the source code and then he just like
starts building up saying um I don't
know the source is from here and then we
reach the sync right we go to this whole
path and then um I've tried to try to uh
like uh do the same thing as as he he
was doing and he has been doing um and
uh yeah um like
but my my favorite kind of stuff are
like memory corruption stuff but uh one
of one of my also other favorite kind of
things to do is like any net related
vulnerabilities uh and I'm just and I'm
not just saying that to promote my own
training even though I have a training
people are like uh welcome to do and I'm
so happy uh I haven't announced it yet
but I'm I'm so happy to say like I have
like a August August training uh coming
up and uh it just it it has been like
filled up right congrats I've had thank
you like it had like 25 seats 24 seats
have been filled up and I'm I'm so happy
about it and like it's crazy like uh uh
when I started like making the training
I thought like you know you whenever you
want whatever you want to start you you
think like I don't know like maybe maybe
nobody likes it or maybe nobody come but
you know like if you build it they'll
they'll show up or whatever and then
I've exactly I I I tried to like give it
as a workshop different places and just
like going to different countries and
different conferences and doing it and
then people people were nice enough to
to post like feedbacks and stuff and
that feedback helped on uh promoting the
the training for other people to show up
and then I've had like 15
registrations uh 15 or 14 registrations
uh until like I don't know three weeks
ago or something two weeks ago and then
after I published I dropped like three
exploit three exploits at the same time
three blog post um with a uh with a
privilege escalation uh after I D
dropped those uh three blog post uh
saying that I'm doing this to promote my
training and then uh people like started
like 14 13 other people signed up for
the training which was so you found ni
way to to get publicity to that and you
found a way to add value to the
community so you know you drop this this
blog post everyone's reading through
this they're like wow this this rocks
and then you know you've got oh let me
check out this guy in his course um so
that's that's really exciting man and
you know this pod is GNA drop soon so
you need to get another you need to get
another class that people can sign up
for or maybe like a weight list or
something because I'm sure a lot of the
listeners to this podcast would love to
uh to sign up and check out this class
especially if you want to get into this
um a little bit deeper realm right like
a lot of the stuff that we talk about
here is um is some you know web related
vulnerabilities and stuff like that but
one of the things we stress all the time
is is if you can get your hands on
source code man that is so sweet like
like if there's any possibility of you
remotely being able to get your hands on
source code uh it's amazing and with net
stuff um that's more and more possible
um and so yeah definitely definitely
check out this course if you're
interested uh we'll link it down in this
description um and and so I guess when
you're dealing with net Stu how do you
how do you how do you approach that what
is your give us a little bit of insight
into your methodology for
net yeah so uh what I do is no magic
like I just do the same thing as many
other people have been doing for years
years and years and years there is to be
honest with you like there isn't there
isn't complet like there isn't much of a
secret sauce it's just it's just doing
the same people do but I just I I I
don't do it like once I do it a thousand
times and then out of those thousand
times maybe five targets are vulnerable
and then people only see the end result
of the blog post coming up right uh but
uh I just like keep doing the same thing
and then um I start like picking up
things um uh with net basically you you
you'll after you like acquire the
software whatever that you think worth
investigating either it's a wellknown I
don't know like a if it's like
well-known software such as like
exchange or SharePoint or like a solar
winds product right like these are like
wellknown products um you get them you
acquire them and then you like install
the software and then you you start to
map out the attack surface but in order
to map out the attack surface you need
to understand like uh like you're
working with like a net Target the good
thing with net is when you can decompile
net and get get get almost like the
exact code that was written initially to
compile it which is amazing like like
Java it ises like you can like de
compile it U given that it hasn't been
like I don't know like minified or off
fiscated which is sometimes a problem
but uh there are ways for that as well
so what are you what are you using for
that did did you me so like are you
using Peak or
or um yeah so there are
lot of softwares that you can use you
can use do Peak uh Rider from jet brains
you can use is spy DN spy Visual Studio
you can use all of those uh and and I
sometimes switch between them sometimes
for some reason one of them doesn't work
and you're like okay let's let me try
the other one or whatever do you have a
preference on that's your first go to I
yeah I usually go with the most generic
one people use DN spy that's like that's
my favorite but but I know a lot of
experts who use like Visual Studio
uh it's a bit it maybe it's a bit like
uh it takes just like a if you haven't
done it before it maybe takes you like
like an hour to to to figure out how to
do it but uh just the first time but you
can use like Visual Studio too but I use
like usually DN spy has always worked
for me um the the latest version of DN
spy is called DN spy X because DN spy
was abandoned and
then yeah DN spy X and then it's funny
um on a like a non-related kind of thing
the the guy who's been developing the N
spy X for the last like I think four
years maybe five years he's like this
like 19yearold 20year old kid no way uh
who yeah he's like he's like a
self-taught do developer his name is um
his handle his Electro kill if I'm not
wrong and is this like genius kind of
dude who's like been adding a lot of
features to to the project and just
taking the project by his own uh people
commit but majority of the like crucial
commits are from things that Evol around
Eng love people like that the dude that
do that massive service to the community
and when you said dnp I went to the old
repo and I was like man this hasn't been
touched in like four years I'm kind of
surprised you're still using this but um
yeah no it makes sense that with DN spy
X and that's ex by the way I I I
searched DN spy just the letter X and it
didn't come up so DN spy ex um very cool
yeah and I know I know that uh that Joel
is a little bit more of a uh of fan of
um a peak and and that whole uh family
of products over there but I think it's
definitely worthwhile to switch between
the two because there are some weird
things sometimes where one will reverse
it and the other one won't and I've seen
this in Java plenty of times as well
because there's so many Java decompilers
as
well yeah so usually like uh giving
giving out some pointers to people this
is this is well know this is like couple
of like well-known things this is not
something that I like that I only know
or like like a like a secret knowledge
or whatever but um with net sometimes
you try to like debug a process and then
for some reason uh either you're not
like you attach to the process and then
you like start putting break points and
then in the end spy or whatever kind of
thing that you're using and then the
break points won't be set the software
kind of like gives you such an error
saying that I can't set a breako here or
you do set the break points um on
different places and then you go and uh
the these like debuggers right whenever
your breakpoint hits you can look at the
local variables Global variables
whatever right it's called the locals
and then you can start looking at them
but
um for some reason you get errors when
you try to find their value like the
software is looking into the memory to
to to find the value or whatever uh
doing some sort of like things behind
the scene but you're not able to see it
that's because with net at least um
there can be different reasons but one
of the reasons which happens like 70% of
time is because the image sot so we call
Net executables like images right we can
call anything image but this doet
executable or image or like DL whatever
it has been optimized U when you execute
a net do that project uh do that runtime
will optimize this DLS and uh and make
them in a way that the debugger isn't
able to uh like pick into the values so
you need to De optimize this kind of
like uh de optimize this uh like the
images and in order to do so there's
like there's a lot of like not a lot but
there's like three four blog posts out
there that says like how to do it
basically you create a inii file next to
the uh image name and then you just like
put some some sort of a allow optimize
uh and some other things in there and
you switch their values to disable them
and then and then you just like kill the
process or like restart restart a
process whatever and then now the next
time that it comes up the uh
the the image isn't optimized anymore
and then the debugger can easily break
point Anywhere work with multi threaded
applications look at locals and
everything because doet has a lot of
concepts of um optimization uh Global
assembly cache and um some other stuff
called engine Next Generation like
engine kind of like images which
basically all kind of uh it can be
explained way more but just like to to
put like an end to to the concept is the
image has been optimized to run faster
or run more efficient so the debugger
can't really work with it for some
reason you need to De optimize it by
putting inii file next to it and then
you all sort it you can start like
debugging this dude that's awesome and I
just want to shout out as well just some
of the copy that was in your in your um
uh sort of description for your course
it was like Hey listen this is 80% stuff
that's that's out there and 20% stuff
that's special to me but you know why
should I pay for something that's 80%
public and and 20% not you answer that
question so El eloquently which is like
like this is this is how people learn
about stuff is getting all of these
these that 80% squared away and there's
a lot more than just that 80% out there
so if you're swimming in this sea of
knowledge right and and what you're
doing with this course is giving them
that that 80% that they need right and
uh and and I think that's absolutely
pivotal you know when you come against
this scenario um and you're just trying
to set up a debugger on this thing and
you're like I can't get it to set the
break points or whatever um that sort of
knowledge is is absolutely pivotal so
what you're paying for with this course
is a way to to lower you know to narrow
in on the stuff that you need to be more
High performing in a net environment
which I think is is very high value um
so I think that's really cool one thing
what U I apologize for jumping in but
one thing I want to say I I always say
that like I kind of like these do these
like small workshops which are like a
couple of hours which is like the which
is you know like the sample of the
training of what what you will get when
you come up for the training uh to to
try to promote my training you know just
like many other people have been doing
for years right just just you got to you
got to start like doing it promote it
yourself and then I I I tell this to
people a lot genuinely the the course is
expensive and I really don't recommend
it if if you're some sort of a uh
student or like a like a solo person
who's like making an earning by himself
to to come up to the course even though
even though I would love saying that oh
come up to my course I'll teach you
everything doesn't matter like who you
are but I I genuinely say this like uh
if you're an individual it just doesn't
add up spending that much money for a
training even though who doesn't love a
students for me it's generating money
right but it's I think it's mostly
preferred if you're working for an
organization or a company that the
company is investing in these like
employees in these vulnerability
researchers to come to somebody's
training who who is advertising that he
can like take you from the basics to
pretty pretty pretty advance in do
exploitation uh for that company the
price makes sense but for an individual
or for an student it doesn't and I get a
lot of emails from people uh who are
students so sorry I get a lot of people
from uh email from people um sending me
email saying like they're kind of like a
student can you give us a discount or
whatever and I we and I have given
discounts for those people and they've
actually signed up but I always say this
like uh you just you can learn all of
these by yourself all of this yourself
just don't think you have to come to my
training or anybody's training you can
learn all of this yourself that's how I
learned it you can just search the
titles go to the blogs each blog will at
least have at least will have one or two
references to other blogs and this just
goes like a like a whole web of stuff
and then you just like keep keep
following it and then after you like
follow these kind of stuff you you next
thing you know like eight eight months
later nine months later you like you
have like a pretty pretty good
foundation now so this is just the fast
TR you know like if you're trying to do
if you're trying to get it quickly if
you're trying to understand exactly what
you need and I like also that it it
makes me trust I haven't taken your
course and and uh you know we haven't
done any deals on like you know
promoting your course for this podcast
but I think I'm much more likely to take
your course because of what you just
explained about foundations and like and
and how much this guy helped you and how
how much that was a part of your
learning experience because what you
want out of these FastTrack courses is
not like solve all my problems what what
what you need is like give me the tools
that I need to solve my own problems
right um when I go up against these
targets so I think that's really
encouraging um so but I do want to push
back a little bit on something you said
which was that this is for organizations
because um I mean how much does this
course cost
it costs like uh 3,000 British
p4,000 you need to yeah yeah and then
you need to like and then when people go
start paying they they see they see the
tax as well on the money and then
they're like oh this is too much money
which makes sense and
um what I wanted to say with this sorry
to interrupt but what I wanted to say
with this was like if you if you're a
bug Bounty Hunter and you're just a Solo
solo bu Bounty Hunter right I do this
full-time I would have no qualms paying
for this course out of my own my own
company you know my own earnings right
because I know that if I use the
techniques in this course um and I I
apply this and I get one just one rce
out of this on some of these more
Enterprise grade targets that pays out
much much more than this $44,000 that
I'm that I'm I'm paying and I I have
just walked away with all those skills
right so not only do I get Roi but I get
the skills as well so I I just think you
know from from my perspective I think
bug bounty hunters are a little
bit I don't know I think there's
something about them that that makes
them want to go this this route of like
you know learn it all yourself build all
the tools yourself that sort of thing
and I think that's excellent um but for
the people that are wanting are getting
frustrated with their bug Bounty journey
and they want to expedite the process a
little bit um and then you know maybe
pivot out of a job where they're unhappy
or something like that doing something
like this paying the money up front and
then expecting to see an Roi I think is
a great is a great move um and a move
that I don't see enough people do invest
in their own education
so yeah like four days 32 hours like you
you you understand like like 90% 95% of
what you need like and and in the
training it's it is a long course and
like all the targets are like willward
sers that I've like like exploited or
like other people have exploited I'll
bring it in class we'll have set it up
and then we'll just go through the whole
chain uh like lot of bucks more than
like 25 bucks lot of chains and like
like all the areas like you'll like
fully understand all the serializers
that are that are out there for net not
just like running wio serial and if it
fails if it fails whatever actually
being able to like craft chains Gadget
chains and like making exploit chains
and all of that and going through that
it to be honest like it is it is pretty
pretty much as I said valuable and I
understand you're saying like B Bounty
punter um I don't know if it's the right
word to use but might have the luxury to
to be able to afford such trainings to
to get that Roi but um again and and I
love students who who doesn't love the
students I love anybody who wants to
sign up I'm I'm happy to I'm I'm making
a living I will do my part to give the
training and I also make getting the
money out of it
uh but if you're like if you're a person
watching this listening to this whatever
right if if you open the website because
back in the day this this is what
happened to me and and I feel and I feel
for these people right uh because this
has happened to me we open up the
website you see the syllabus you see the
guy who's teaching it you're like oh
okay you first if you get first you need
to get convinced if the guy knows his
[__] right and then you're like okay
okay he he might know something right I
believe he knows something
I want to go to training sounds
interesting but this is too much money I
can't AFF it don't don't let that stop
you from pursuing net exploitation just
do it like just copy paste the
syllabuses that I have and just keep
searching you have a you have a problem
you don't understand it I put my email
out there just copy paste it send an
email saying can you give me some
references that I want to understand
this topic or that topic I'm happy to do
so I don't want to hold it back because
because I'm not you're not taking out
anything from me it is something that I
learn from other people as well I'm just
giving you references to go learn it it
will take me five minutes to give you
that link to go learn it and and people
have and and I I've said this is not the
first time I'm saying this I've said it
in like different like classes and
conferences I've been to and this has
actually impacted people and they've
they've WR they have been writing me
emails saying oh we want to understand
like how to exploit this kind of
serializer that has been implemented in
net can you give can afford the training
can you give us some references on
places that we can go read about this
whatever right and I and I've like send
them links I'm I'm happy to that's a
that's a great offer don't don't let
people don't let that to stop you you
can do it absolutely like one nine
months eight months one year if you if
you do it constantly you do it like this
like it's nothing it's easy it's not
black magic it's not it's not like
secret knowledge I've learned it by
Googling you can do it too uh yeah no
that's a great offer man I think I think
um I think that you know you kind of
open up the floodgates a little bit
there so be careful because what'll end
up happening is is you you'll you'll
start getting you know people messaging
you like f to be honest that's that's
great well hey man take advantage of
this offer while it lasts with with him
because um you know at some point he's
going to get to the point where he can't
um he can't reply reply to all of them
so while while he he's offering this
take advantage of it okay so um yeah so
Cena I wanna I want to move over to a
topic that you sort of mentioned before
and then uh something you also have in
the notes saying that a debugger is
super important to you um and I have a
little confession to make here on the
Pod I have not set up a debugger on like
an active debugger on a on a Target that
I've worked on before I've done so much
uh you know white box um you know source
code review that sort of thing but it's
always been me looking at the code me
crafting an exploit me sending it in and
then being like you know why the freck
isn't this working you know and not
having any introspection into it and
when I think about the luxury of having
a debugger I'm like oh man that would
make this process so much easier um so
for for those of us that haven't
actually had um that experience before
can you talk a little bit about what
that adds to you and then how just at a
high level how how difficult it is to
set it up in various environments like a
Java environment or a or a net
environment uh that's that's actually a
really good question even I was the same
back in the day I I would like look at
the source code if it was like a web app
and I'd be like okay this is a function
is taking two like input arguments from
the query string or maybe the post body
or whatever or maybe a header I can see
it clearly in this code and then it's
it's I don't know passing it to like a
SQL query without sanitization okay I
understand it I just need to hit the
send point with my rep seet or whatever
and provide those arguments and then I
will hit it right
and most of the times that works right
yeah um but at a certain point in time
you you you come across applications
which are far more complicated uh and
then for some reason you're trying to
send those parameters or whatever either
it's a TC it's a TCP server which has
been written in cc++ that you need GDB
to attach to it's a compiled binary or
it's a net Target which you need to
attach D inspite to it or it's like a
Java Target which you need to attach
like its own debugger to it either it's
I don't know like you need can use like
jet brains products or any kind of other
product you want to use to to debug to
debug it and then for some reason you're
not hitting that end point rep is I
don't know you're giving like a 404 or
an unauthorized or whatever if you're
doing only source code review and it's
like a huge application you might
think why doesn't it work should I move
on maybe the code is dead or whatever or
maybe some you don't know that thing
right somebody's inside myin that's
exactly what I say in my brain I'm like
why isn't this working I could see the
source code like
exactly you say like I'm seeing it like
either see my de compiler disassembler
or whatever I'm seeing it like why isn't
it being hit but when you attach a
debugger to that like to that Target if
it's say like a Java Target you like use
like a many debuggers for Java but like
I usually use like jet brains product
for Java targets you you attach to it
and then you understand okay there is a
filter or an Interceptor or a middle
which is which is like way way way
before this route gets called and that's
looking for certain header that I'm not
sending yet and that's why for example
I'm not reaching this sync reaching this
function or whatever that helps or
sometimes you want to bypass mitigations
uh and you want to keep testing for it
or or fuzz the behavior or whatever
when you attach a debugger you can in
most of these in most of these uh
debuggers you can start uh writing
Expressions right you can write Java
code or net code uh or like Peck into
the memory or change stuff and then call
a function again and again and again uh
and then that kind of like speeds up
your analysis and your
understanding uh
exactly and which is which is perfect
I've I've actually started with
debuggers uh like with like GDB I was
just mostly debugging like low level
stuff just like picking to the memory
not no extension no Jeff no P Pawn dvg
or Pawn bag whatever you want to call it
no win dvg or win bag whatever uh none
of those I was just like using like pure
like classic GDB for embedded
exploitation most of that and then I've
and then I was just as I was like doing
more like web app and like net Java I
was like setting up PHP debuggers net
debuggers Java debug and all of that and
then setting up a debuger helps a lot it
is painful sometimes and that and people
choose to move on I have I have chose to
move on sometimes but as I grew I've
learned to don't move on and whatever it
takes just have it set up I kid you not
uh in some of the pwn toon targets that
we worked on there were some like exotic
architectures that they don't have they
don't have it's called an art
like a real time operating system so
it's not like a Linux or whatever that
you can get a shell and then you you can
upload a debugger or whatever right it's
a real- Time operating system and you
need to when you want to debug stuff you
got to like open up the device and like
attack some attach some sort of like a
physical device and all of that and just
like it's pretty pretty painful and then
when you go through that you're like
okay that takes like 10 hours how long
it's going to take me to like set up
this Java debugger okay 1 Hour 2 hour
let's let's just do it right it works so
so okay I'm sold I'm sold you you sold
me on the debugger thing that's great so
so that but the next thing is kind of
what I want to ask about is is like how
does this work with various targets
right because you're attacking these iot
devices you know you don't have access
to the firmware specifically you know
you don't necessarily have access to
this um you know Docker container of the
operating system or anything like that
um and you want to get one of these
things set up uh how do you do you get
that set up and then also you know in in
a scenario where you're dealing with
like a net application or whatever that
has like um you know it's own Docker
image or something like that uh how are
you how are you reaching into that
Docker image and setting up this
debugger um versus like something in in
the iot world where you've got like a
physical device that you don't have an
image
for uh yeah uh okay I think uh I think I
understand the question uh please please
try to jump in if if it wasn't the right
answer or if if you felt like this is
not the answer to a question uh most of
the time I don't know if it's like a
Java Target if it's on a Windows or a
Linux uh you need to understand how the
Java Java process is being started and
then you can like provide arguments to
that to that command that's starting the
Java process and then when you provide
arguments to it you can you can enable
like Java debug by protocol like jdw or
like other stuff to to enable debugging
which exposes a de debugging service
that you can uh connect to with your
debugger most debuggers allow remote
debugging so that's what Java so so for
Java let me just let me just Echo this
back to you so I can make sure that I
understand it yeah you know for Java
let's say we've got a Docker container
it it spins up this Java app or whatever
with the jar file you find whatever like
Dosh file or whatever that's being run
that triggers that Java command you know
Java D jar whatever right and then you
you modify that file us and and you say
Okay um now I'm going to turn on
debugging and then maybe you got to open
the port in in or whatever and then and
then you can connect to that debugging
Port uh via your debugger and it will
allow you to just jump right in and
control that that flow of the
application yeah exactly uh yeah um you
got it right you have this Docker image
you will try to get a shell on the
docker image modified in some sort of a
way to to enable like some sort of
arguments to the to the to the to the
Java starter command or whatever Bas
script or whatever it is in order to
allow to enable debugging that's what
Java usually
that's the trick right there are some
special cases too but usually that's the
way to do it as far as my knowledge goes
um can you hear me right yes yeah
absolutely so so so for for like
something like net um yeah you know I
imagine it's a little different are you
like loading up a A dll or something
like that or or how are you addressing
that yeah so with net you just like uh
you have different kind of debuggers uh
but like with with the ins SP usually
what happens is this is use DN spy to
dpy has like a debugger debugger feature
you can you can attach to processes or
launch a process oh when you launch a
process you can start immediately
debugging from the program start when
you attach to a process you attach to
its current state whatever it is at the
time that you're attaching to um
attaching to it and then you you attach
to it and then you can start debugging
but sometimes when you start start
debugging that Target process in net you
start seeing okay my break points are
not even hit so you need to do that op
the optimization trick that I told you
about that you just place an file next
to it with some sort of value and then
you just restart the process and then
you attach it again um there are some
special cases too but these are the
usual things that happen with iot stuff
like embedded stuff most of most of the
times if it's if it's a device which is
like Linux based has like an operating
system or whatever um you you want to
like push GDB to the device so you have
like a a statically compiled GDB client
or a GDB server you push to the device
you upload it in some sort of a
way taking considering you already
gained a shell on the device because
with iot stuff when you get the device
first you need to acquire a initial
shell on the device um so let me ask
about that process really quickly so so
yeah um I also want to go back to the
net thing for a second because I I would
like to ask about um remote debugging
with net because in in the scenario that
you that you had um you know we're we're
in the same environment we can just
attach to the process or whatever but if
we're doing like let's say we're running
this unet application in like a you know
a different environment is there some
way to connect from like a from like a
remote context for that as far as I know
this this is as far as my knowledge goes
I don't know if it's possible to debug a
net process remotely with Java it
exposes a port that you can connect to
it
remotely uh so basically it runs a
lessener but with net as far as I know D
Inspire attaches to the process and uses
Windows debugging apis and Ms Corb which
is Microsoft like Microsoft library for
do like CLR the common language run time
these are like do specific Technologies
and engines and uses those to debug into
that process to attach to that process
to debug it um but I don't I haven't
heard about somebody debugging AET
process remotely yeah that makes sense
okay so so moving moving to the iot side
then when you're approaching this
Hardware Target for like an event or
whatever obviously you got to get this
initial shell to get you know your your
debugger set up and on it right so um I
feel like there's only two approaches to
this there's like Hardware hacking
techniques right where you've got your
Ur you've got your JTAG you've got um
you know glitching related stuff that
sort of thing um or you got to go
blackbox and you gotta you know you
gotta try to pop it without actually uh
you know having the source code or
whatever I guess there's one third
option as well which is like if you can
get your hand on the firmware
then you can sort of be white box but
still not have a debugger um what is
your go-to flow with that and how do you
address all of these three
possibilities yeah that's a great
question uh so in order to like start
researching like a iot device uh
basically first you need to like get the
device after you got the device you want
to interface with the device right you
want to get a shell on it assuming it's
a Linux based system not some sort of
Ras or whatever and then you can use
like some sort of like a art JTAG what
never to interface with the device once
you do interface with the device if it
has like a some sort of a console you
try to like usually after the console
you have you have unlimited shell like
you have like a root shell or whatever
and you want to buy you want to get
around it basically what I'm what I'm
answering is the usual answer right it
there can be a there can be different
scenarios special cases as well which
happen often uh but um in order to
bypass that kind of like a console
either you guess the password or you can
guess the password but sometimes the
password has been public by someone else
or whatever it's like a maybe like a
roote 123 or a wender name or whatever
and then if you can't get around it then
you can like use glitching sometimes
glitching helps almost all the time
glitching Works glitch glitching is
super powerful if you master it like sky
is the limit and then you can like use
like glitching to get around that
protected shell um if you do that's one
way sometimes the firmware is available
on the vendor website you can just get
the firmware back to the firmware and
install the firmware on the device and
just get a shell that's it right
sometimes it can happen uh sometimes you
just got to like yolow it and then
you're like okay I've I've I just take
the chip off and then just read the chip
and then write to the chip back door the
frame whatever repack it repack it and
then just put the put the chip back but
you need to like know dis like soldering
dis soering like all that um and
sometimes the chip on the device is not
like a like a like a like a simple
normal flash chip or whatever it's like
a emmc or BGA which you usually see them
in phones so when you like dis it or
like take it out um you you need to know
how to do
reballing which not anyone can
do exactly you got to have like steady
hands and like do a clean job uh
sometimes there is some sort of wiggle
room for you to like mess up just a bit
you don't need to you don't need to be
perfect in doing it but sometimes which
I which I've did actually for for Ponto
2024 Pon in Japan I I had to we were
targeting these infotainment systems uh
which are like infotainment for cars and
then most of the times you couldn't
actually find like you had to like
desolder it at least for me like for a
lot of them I had to desolder them and
then uh the device is so expensive like
I don't know two grand three grand four
grand you can just buy two or whatever
uh so you need to like desolder it and
you need to do know reballing to put the
chip chip back and then to to to use
your shell or whatever to go on the
device and start working on on it but
sky is the limit as I said sometimes and
then maybe maybe maybe sometimes even
you don't need to make it more difficult
maybe sometimes blackbox you can find a
command injection in the application and
you just get a root shell that's it
right uh so maybe try to go with the
easier approaches um is is so man that's
that's a two grand device I know that
that I've only had one or two
experiences you know hacking an iot
device where I actually have to like
pull the chip off get it readed pull the
firm that sort of thing but in the first
time I did it you know I I was literally
like I was shaking you know and this is
like a $60 device that they gave me for
free you know like and and so are you do
you guys have to buy your own devices
for these competitions or are they like
pomping you for the devices at all
afterwards if you find a valid
bug uh no usually with 99% of the
targets you need to buy them yourself
and then and then sometimes sometimes
the the device is only available
like us and like you're like another
like continent or something and then and
then they like the device is only sold
in us
so goes to your imagin system to get
your hands on the
device how difficult is to to to get the
product to you and uh yeah um it gets it
gets difficult but but uh worth
mentioning for like targets like Tesla
right so you want to Target Tesla right
if you're a well-known res researcher or
you have done Tesla exploits before for
zero day initiative Pon toon competition
uh Pon toon will provide you with not a
car they don't they don't they don't
send car all right extra incentive
here yeah not not not not a car but they
will uh send you the the the correct
ecus that you need the the the computer
in the in the car the the the ISU that
you need that that are part of the
attack surface that are accepted uh so
you need to like wire the ecus and
whatever and make sure when you like
plug in it plug it into your outlet you
don't burn the ECU or whatever and then
you can you can like set it up and then
just like start finding bugs on it but
you need like that's not for someone who
who just wants to come to Ponto like the
first day and then they will give him
like eus or whatever give him or her
whatever U it depends on that kind of
like relationship that you have with the
organizers and Tesla knows you and all
of that kind of stuff but that's crazy
man yeah yeah that's that's nuts and and
I I want to ask so you know this is a
high-risk environment for you you're
buying these these these you know these
things I know that I burned through four
chips I think the first time I was
trying to pull pull a chip out you know
just just from lack of experience and I
and I I did better afterwards you know I
bought I think like 10 of the devices or
whatever and I was able to finally get
it consistently but um you know when
you're going into it it's a it's a
pretty high investment environment um so
how how much of the time time would you
say that you're dealing with um I can
just connect to art or JTAG and get a
Shell versus I have to pull the firmware
via you know pulling the chip the EMC
chip and and getting it into a reader
and getting it to read um versus like a
blackbot uh blackbox approach versus
like firmware like what what is the
distribution of those four what is most
common and what is least
common
uh let let me think how how to
you're you're asking pretty solid
questions uh that's why that's why
you're getting me hooked on it um yeah
so basically like in the first like I
think in the first like 12 hours or 10
hours I'll kind of like exhaust all the
possibilities that I can get a shell
except the blackbox kind of thing like
in the like first eight or 10 hours I
I'll I'll exhaust all the hardware
related kind of techniques that I that I
am aware of that I can maybe launch
against this target uh
10 hour is it enough isn't it enough I
don't know it's just it's just the way
that I do it and then after if I don't
get a shell in that like 10 hours or or
I conclude that okay after this 10 hours
I've I've exhausted all the simple
tricks that I could do now it doesn't
work in the 10 hours either I'm going to
go blackbox or maybe maybe if I would
maybe if I would have gone with blackbox
I would have find it in the first five
minutes who knows you don't know that
that's just me
and then or I would be like okay I will
invest more time on glitching it at the
right time because because you might say
why don't you always just take the chip
off because sometimes the chip is
encrypted and then the keys are like are
are stored somewhere else or like you
need to talk to this like the system on
chip or
whatever yeah like or or it's in an
enclave or something um and it's not as
easy as that so uh some sometimes you
kind of like in the 10 first 10 hour
I'll conclude either I want to go fa
fault injection fully or I just want to
like be like okay I can't do anything I
I just got a black boxes somehow and
then find a way
in what's your intuition on the order
like of of how often these work so to
like you know 50% of the time youart
gives me a Shell or like you know what's
your intuition on like how how often
these various techniques
work the the most often way that I use I
just use art if if the
I just use Ard and then I combine it
with glit glitching and then you get a
shell you definitely get a shell at
least for for me this is this is from I
don't represent like all the people who
have done this kind of research this is
just this my answer U for me I just
combine like I just connect with your
sometimes you have a shell which you
don't see it often happening at least
for targets anymore uh they're like high
value targets uh so so they've been well
tested kind of uh this the easy the easy
doors have been closed and then I just
combine it with like glitching and then
most of the times they don't have any
protection against glitching and then I
just that that that's my way in uh uh
that's my usual go-to and then if that
doesn't work uh I'll go for the chip if
that doesn't work uh Black Box okay
gotcha wow that's that's a that's pretty
cool so so a lot of times you know I
think it might be worthwhile for me to
invest a little bit into understanding
how glitching Works a little bit uh a
little bit better better glitching and
fault injection because um yeah once you
go that route with the when you're
pulling the chip off it's I've never
soldered a chip back on successfully you
know and gotten it to read um that's
very hard to do um and and I think you
need some more Advanced Equipment than
what I've got as well if just got a you
know beginner Hardware hacking setup
here with like my hot air gun and and uh
you know a [__] ton of flux and that
sort of thing so um that that's really
interesting to hear that that fault
injection um and that sort of thing is
is a more combon approach for you to to
get through there um Okay cool so now
you know we've gone through that path
we've got a shell on this device um what
are now now we're getting a debugger set
up live on that that actual device so
you're kind of looking through the the
file system you're you're trying to
figure out what is starting the you know
web interface or the whatever TCP
interface or whatever and then you're
hooking into that is that is that the
idea yeah so you once you have a shell
now hopefully you'll start like
understanding what's available as the
attack surface right the goal is getting
remote code execution without user
interaction on this device and one other
thing that you need to you need to
consider is sometimes you need to
sometimes P Pon says for example these
kind of services are out of question
right we don't want if an exploit is
impacting these we don't want it even
though even though you you are achieving
remote code execution but if it's
targeting this service we don't want it
uh so because
this this is this has kind of like
recently came up in Ponto in in the last
in the last few years you wouldn't be
dealing with it as much as it might
sound but uh it can happen that for
example they say I don't know this
routers on this router any any exploit
on the upm service universal plug and
play we don't want it because up pmps
are are in these targets are not made by
the vendor they made by the thir third
party even though even though you might
come and say okay doesn't matter the
vendor the client is using it right but
but for some reason they they they have
their own reasons right and they're the
organizers
so it's their rules it's their their
game right they say like we don't want
it right they have their own reasons and
then so you might not want to be looking
at it but basically you find Services uh
you exclude the ones that should be
excluded and then you start working on
them to to see if you can uh trigger
anything remotely basically what's what
are the open ports
sending a packet to each Port what does
it do what does it trigger what service
does it work with you take the service
you try to as is it DEC compilable you
de compile it disassemble it whatever
you set up a debugger you you attach to
it you start analyzing all what's
available you find for danger you look
for Dangerous behaviors you do you
utilize your static analysis you set up
a fuzzer it can be a blackbox fuzzer a
dumb fuzzer you kind of like develop
your intuition on making a bit faster
and better fuzzer you make like a
snapshot based fuzzing with like
emulation you make a grammar for your
fuzzer you make it them better and
better to like start harvesting memory
corruption vulnerabilities and when I
said that I set the sentence maybe like
in one or two minute two minutes but it
having like emulation set up in your
local server or like in your remote
server to fuzz the same binary that was
so so you have this target which has
like I don't know one gig of RAM or
whatever two gigs of RAM or or maybe
like megabytes right you have this
device and you want to take which has
its own tool chain which has its own
like operating system whatever you take
this architecture everything right
everything like and it's not like using
the word saying everything on it is
living in an Harmony together it's just
some sort of a [__] glue together which
is like some sort of abomination that
they've managed to like just make it
work and then you just want to take like
one piece of that
and put it on the latest Linux version
on your server of course it's not going
to work right of course but it you need
to yeah never usually never happens so
you need to set up like your own like
emulation with like Kimo or whatever you
want to use unicorn Kimo chilling
whatever is all frame okay hold hold up
hold up hold so you just so I've heard
I've heard of uh Kimu right qemu but
what what were the other ones you
mentioned yeah Unicorn it's unicorn
engine unicorn
some same same thing for for emulation
the other one it's it's written killing
which is q i l iing g okay but but as
far as I know the author of the author
of it the guy who wrote it says chilling
so I'm saying chilling as well but it's
killing whatever yeah okay it's also
it's it's a wrapper around unicorn
engine which you can utilize to to write
emulation and even a snapshot based fuz
but the most powerful one that I recom
people to go is using things like just
like being able to like use like AFL
with a combination of chemo if you can
like slap those together and then make
it work lib AFL is a is a pretty
powerful is a pretty pretty pretty
powerful Library written in Rust so you
got to know how to code in Rust that
that kind of like that's that's kind of
like a showstopper to a lot of people
but uh it's definitely recommended to to
to be able to do it okay as far as you
can yeah if you can get Kimo and AFL
working that's that that's a decent
option there there are better options
too why not but that's good enough yeah
that that makes a lot of sense as far
modern knowledge goes so so I'm I'm
diving into your whole flow here okay
I'm I'm I'm breaking apart the whole the
whole brain so we we we get a a hold of
a shell somehow likely via Hardware
hacking but potentially you know via
dumping the firmware and then finding a
a bug with just just code review and
then popping it and then getting a sh
then we're taking all the binaries
taking all the different pieces of the
environment decompiling it if we can
whatever we're getting our exactly um
this exactly and then we go Kimu and
then we go um or any of these other uh
emulation softwares to get the correct
environment get the correct um uh you
know libraries or whatever in the you
don't have to but for for for fuzzing or
like having your local setup for like
because because you so
why do you do it I said before you want
to fuzz this Abomination but it's
running on a device which is too a slow
so if you want to blast it with like a
million requests either it's going to
just like die or reboot or whatever so
if you manage to take it out and put it
on a on your own machine which has like
128 gig of RAM or like I don't know a
ton of cores and it's like Fast uh all
that you can just like because uh I
don't I I'm I'm going to say this you're
an expert obviously but I'm going to say
for for for people who don't know right
so you have this binary which is a uh I
don't know uh imagine imagine this this
device is a smart speaker right this
smart speaker understands parsing MP3
files right and the way it works is the
web server will receive MP3 file and
then will somehow pass this MP3 file to
this executable right yeah you want to
you want to fuzz This MP3 parser you
want to you want to because you know
maybe you can find a memory coruption on
this MP3 parser so you can find a memory
coruption on the speaker and get code
execution that way right ah I see either
you can go by uploading MP3 files to the
web server which the web server needs to
process your HTTP request take the MP3
file save the MP3 file pass the MP3 file
to the MP3 parser MP3 parser goes to the
initialization phase to come up as a
process to allocate some memory load its
libraries all of that basically an
active process and then opening it opens
the file reads the file start parsing it
you went through I don't know nine steps
to get to the parsing but with a
snapshot based fuzzing you can eliminate
all of those eight steps take the file
and wrote a snapshot snapshot based
fuzzer it it's it's set it can easily be
set but it's not easily done you can set
up your snapshot base fuzer to tell your
snapshot base fuzer to if if if this is
the function which is uh at this is
again this is a compiled binary it's not
source code it's it's compile right if
if at this function in this in this
binary this offsets in memory right if
this function this sub routina starts
and it starts parsing This MP3 file and
it ends here and there a thousand other
functions before and after it we just
want to fuzz this so I want you to con
to to change the flow of execution to
here and go until here
and then and then when it reaches end
here you go back and then you revert the
snapshot revert the state of the memory
to what it was because you you you got
to understand either you're fuzzing a
stateless or a state fold kind of like
function uh may may because maybe
because uh maybe when you're fuzzing
this like a sub routine or whatever
maybe it changes something Global if
this is what you want to fuzz maybe it
changes something Above It Right Above
It Out outside of your area and then if
if that thing changes a lot it causes a
crack
which doesn't happen normally it only
happens in your local testing
environments right now I'm getting too
technical but this is exact what we need
to know so for these snapshot fuzzers
you're isolating a specific block of
this you know compiled code right so
you're doing this you know looking at
assembly and you're just essentially
priming the environment that this is is
run in with the memory offsets Etc and
you're just running it over and over and
over again with different inputs to see
what's triggering the the the breakage
and now I want to ask you this okay cuz
my intuition as a web hacker would be
show the device get the source code look
at the web interfaces or or any of the
external facing um Services right that
that would be my my first thing whereas
it seems to me that you Ed the external
interfaces like okay this web interface
and then you just skipped over the web
interface and you're like and the web
interface calls this binary with the MP3
and now I'm going to grab this binary
and fuzz the heck out of it is that
because you are more interested in
fuzzing a as a hacker like that's the
thing that you're interested in right
now or is that because you've seen more
success in this environment going after
the lower level things the lower level
binaries that sort of thing um in the
sort of abomination of a setup of an iot
device right versus going after the the
web interface
stuff yeah so
uh I've um I just want to build up on
what you said um the the more it depends
on you but with P to on usually the more
difficult your exploit is the better
chance it's not going to get duped so uh
es skipping es skipping the web server I
won't SK skip it to be honest for the
snap for writing the snapshot based
fuzzer to implement the snapshot based
fuzzer idea I need to skip it but while
it's while okay the fuzzer is done now
it's fuzzing I have time now I can spend
it I'm looking at the web server right
and I do find a I do and then I found
the command injection in the first
request of the login page what right
obviously it's going to be found by
everyone and obviously it's going to be
patched the last second so I shouldn't
stop at that I should find as many bugs
as possible hoping that at least one of
them will survive it is a cruel kind of
way to look at it but that's just a fact
because I'm I'm ready until the last
second of the competition I'm ready my
full chain is ready uh I have three bugs
in my chain I'm I'm taking I'm catching
a flight I'm in I don't know Vancouver
Toronto whatever right I arrive 10
minutes before the competition the
vendor pushes the over theair update
just either either killing one of the
bugs in the chain or killing all the
killing all the bugs in the chain or
even sometimes what happened to me was
they didn't kill any bugs They just
added a feature or added even a string
doesn't matter added something to the
Buy
that will shift the offset in a way that
my exploit will fail right because my
exploit is like using some sort of I
don't know like a Rob chain and it's
relying on some sort of offset or
something aligned at some place you must
be furious so exactly right so that
that's why that's kind of actually I
feel like they should give you a version
of the app like okay the the product as
it exists at you know July 15th at 11:57
a.m. you know like as it exists in
moment that is what you're you're going
up against but they don't do that they
say the most current patch of the device
and they can patch the device in leading
up to the competition
day yeah is zdi aware of this like I
feel like zdi would like because for for
hacker one you know when we have weird
like this it wow it is a zdi rule so for
for hacker one when we have situations
like this they they they intervene for
us they come in and they say hi up
listen guys you know clearly Justin had
an rce here because he just handed you
your your Etsy password file um you know
even though it's it got patched he
shelled it you know so you you still owe
a bounty right but but maybe that isn't
the case in the zdi
environment no so all of these rules
aren't made by the vendor right it's
made by zdi and and the the motto is we
want to make this as real W as possible
we're targeting real word software at
real time we're not we're not it's it
it's not a done deal with a vendor so
the the the targets that you see in zdi
they haven't accepted to be being in pwn
they haven't chose to be in pwn they've
been brought to Pontoon zdi just puts up
the targets the vend doesn't have a
saying that we want we want this to be
there or we don't want this to be there
they they c yeah they can take the
initiative to to approach CDI saying we
have our devices tested or whatever yeah
they can't take the initiative to to to
approach CDI with putting something
there but they can't take the initiative
coming saying oh we don't want our
product to be tested it's not their call
to make zdi will test it zdi will take
zdi will purchase the bug if if there is
a bug and will immediately report it to
the vendor whether the vendor likes it
or not so the zdi wants to get the box
fixed whether the when uh wants to not
so is there is there any meta strategy
when it comes to this then because I
imagine the
the people that are not actively
involved in the competition right the
person that doesn't have a rep in the
slack group or whatever they are
probably going to be more um malicious
towards the hackers right where it's
like okay we're looking at our logs
we're determining okay somebody's got a
command injection over here so we're
going to patch that you know now uh and
pushing pushing updates over versus the
people that are actually in the slack or
whatever whatever you however you guys
do it in interacting with the the people
that are actively researching their
products is there so is there any
strategy there do you want to go for the
the the there is no communication there
there is no communication with the zero
the only communication you have is with
zdi either so so you you'll so this is
how it works the researcher will uh you
see you see the targets you choose what
you want to work on you go work on it if
you have questions you set it to zdi if
you have any questions this is this
service out of the scope I have this
question or assumption is it is this
considered zero click is this consider
zra whatever zdi will as fast as
possible as best as possible will get
back to you immediately answering your
question uh and then whatever right you
do that and then you just find your bik
write your explo chain you show up at
the competition you execute it and done
if it's done you
immediately you and with zdi employees
employees will immediately like like two
seconds later you're you're sitting in a
room talking to the vendor
directly like like with like a web
whatever right you're talking to the
vendor director and you're disclosing
The Bu to them with CDI right and then
you're getting the bu patched right so
all the communications that you have is
with zdi if there is anything to be uh
made sure of zdi will contact the vendor
kind of on behalf of you kind of wow
that's a very different world man just
to give you some introspection into the
live hacking event um because we do want
to kind of discuss the pone to own
versus hacker one live hacking event
sort of flow here um you know when we
get the invite for the live hacking
event um there's a scope call that
happens and that Scope Call uh is
actually the the person the target
saying like hey this is what we want you
to attack this is what our bounties are
here's what our bonuses are whatever
right and we're here to help whenever
you have any questions right so then
they spin up this slack group and
they're they've got employees in there
they've got like channels where it's
like hey you know if you got any
questions about the architecture if you
have questions about like um you know
are you seeing this ssrf hitting your
internal servers or whatever like that
sort of thing they've got all that set
up and available for you to help the
researcher as much as possible um find
the Vols within within their system and
and sometimes you know some of these
programs are more respons responsive
than not you know um and vice versa but
um at the end of the day typically the
program is on your side and they are
like trying to help you along the way as
much as possible and they want to pay
out as many bounties as they can because
um that means that their attack surface
is getting more secured and they want to
uh you know they want to get budget to
do these events again so that they can
you know get more more bounties and get
more bug submitted and get their attack
surface more secure and that's very
different it seems from the pwn to own
environment and I imagine a lot of that
is because of the fact that pwn to own
competitions are not optional you know
for the vendor it's it's like we're
gonna hack for [__] and you have to
allocate a resour not yeah yeah that's
crazy yeah exactly uh so you you said
something good right you said uh that
would uh the V the vendor wants to spend
the budget to make stuff secure and
everything yeah so it that thing that
that kind of like the the Goodwill right
is in Ponto as well but the wendor is
not spending money it's it's zdi's
budget who's being spent on making these
products
safer it's not like they're charging the
vendor or they're getting money from the
vendor or the vendor is providing budget
to them no they can do a sponsorship
like Google Google is is nice enough to
show up and a sponsor sometimes I don't
know Samsung I think I don't think
Samsung is like senology I'm sure they
did syy is another company um that's
like a n network equipment routers and
stuff like senology has been sponsored
Google and I think Tesla as well they
can sponsor but I don't know if it's
like a lexark printer or a tplink router
tplink is not paying any money or like
like or other someone else as
as far as I know they're not paying any
money and the zdi is spending the budget
and one might ask then why is zdi doing
such a thing like is it just doing it
for in that's it the Goodwill right so
uh zdi is a organization part of Trend
Micro right so it's called Trend Micro
zero day initiative and then uh Brian
gorence uh who is the director of the uh
zero day initiative uh and
which like basically manages Z
initiative uh what what he does is so uh
we have they make a product at uh train
micro does that zero initiative work
with TR train micro they can make a
product um I've uh I I think I've I
forgot the product name but I can find
it uh they make a product uh I think
it's called Tipping Point if I'm not
wrong Tipping Point is a is intrusion
detection system that uh Trend m makes
that has actual zero day protection I'm
not I'm not talking about jokes I'm not
talking about just saying that you have
zero day protection or whatever you you
have so they have immediately when when
when they purchase the box from P to
immediately minutes later the signatures
are already pushed to the device and
ready to defend against that attack and
that's that's their gold as far as I
know that's the golden product kind of
that's called Tipping Point that is
being sold to like um like value
organizations and important customers uh
and it's very crucial and then that's
that that's the way that this whole
thing goes and zero the initiative is
also uh interested in the techniques
that the researchers use because the
rchain that I make is different than the
r chain the other guy makes and maybe in
my R chain I use a technique which is
not that well known and that's
interesting to zero day zero day
initiative researchers to kind of learn
that knowledge and apply it to different
kind of targets and stuff so you're
selling your exploit and your research
knowledge both at the same time and your
exploit is being you mentioned before
that that when you I think this was off
air but um that when you submit a bug
you have to submit a white paper along
with that bug describing the
vulnerability right exactly so so the
tech
documented yeah yes so so at the end you
need to provide a white paper and you
exploit fully and you need to explo your
explain your exploit and your white
paper sorry for the bad English you need
to explain both of them uh to the uh to
the V the initiative researchers uh and
sometimes the vendor as well but it all
gets done in in exactly the same day
when you're do the explo it's not there
is there is nothing going back and forth
with with zero initiative researchers
they're beasts like they even if you
don't explain anything they understand
it like they're wow I can't emphasize
how tented they are I think one of the
most talented researchers that exist
vulnerability researchers like I'm not
saying they're the only one but they are
truly one of the ones that are truly
talented and they work there and then
they can understand your exploit like
like a cake like it's easy to them and
yeah so you need to at the end provide a
white paper with your whole walk through
of what you did why you did it how does
it work everything okay gotcha wow that
that's great so so yeah very there are
some differences between these two
competitions here and that's what I kind
of want to go through now you know and
continue going through that so so
there's no there's no interaction sort
of before the actual event with the
actual team besides getting the scope
and and that comes from zdi and then um
so how much time do you normally have
before the the event occurs so they
release okay the here are the targets
here's the scope or whatever how much
time before you're onsite demoing your
your exploit and what does that
pre-event look like
so two to three months is usually what
you have um if I'm not miscalculating
stuff um which I'm really bad at with
I'm really bad with the dates and stuff
um time frames but I think it's like
almost kind of like around something
near two months to three months uh that
that's your kind of time frame before
the competition deadline reaches and
then you're at the stage and you're
launching your exploit or whatever if
you're participating remotely and if if
you find a bug and you want to apply to
attend the competition and you
participated remotely you will send your
white paper and your uh exploit uh to
the uh to the vendor to sorry to not not
the vendor to Z initiative to zdi yeah
and then they they take it and then they
make sure like you're legit because
you're you're coming remotely you can be
like an imposter or whatever so because
they're allocating time uh but if you
come in person then you're good uh uh
you can just show you can just provide
just just just enough details and then
you show up and you launch your exploit
how far in events do you have to
register for that like is that you know
like you can do that up to like two
weeks before the competition or when do
you register it's it's usually up to one
week before the competition wow and and
do they sponsor travel for people that
have you know that are coming in person
or is it self sponsor
Sometimes some sometimes this is
sometimes they try to sometimes they
they they they pay for the travel uh and
the the way that they do it is um they
say that if you're a previous pontoon
winner winner doesn't mean number one
winner so pontoon calls a win when you
have a successful
exploit if you can pull off a successful
exploit on this stage and there is no
dup with anyone they call it a full win
that's a full win if you can be the
number one at the competition then
you're the m of paone so those are
different things if you managed to have
a successful attempt with no do with
anyone previously at pone to like the
the the the competition before before
the one that is going to be happening H
they say okay as a token of appreciation
for you putting the time in again will
uh give you this amount of time this
amount of money to to support you to
come to the competition again wow very
cool so so this is a similar system a
bit to to hacker one which is um there
are two types of invites there's um like
first tier invites I I guess and then
there's like second tier invites these
second tier invites are normally the
result of a first tier invite um plus
oneing you so the anyone who gets a
first tier invite gets their their
travel sponsored uh their hotel and
their flight and that sort of thing and
that doesn't necessarily mean they've
performed well at a live hacking event
before it just means that they have
performed well on the hacker one
platform or against this Target and we
selected for for this competition and
then the tier one invites can say say
all right I'd like to also take uh you
know Cena with me on this trip right and
then they send they select you if they
select you from the plus one list then
you get an invite as well but you have
to sponsor your own travel um cool and
so uh there's that sort of setup which I
think is really cool the the the
difference between
man see listen listen P to on is like
Mortal Kombat like it's like it's you go
there you got to fight for the last
right you don't have you don't
have it is professional it is
professional yeah as much as possible as
as I could think of right but um let me
say it's harder it's harder to pull off
I think I think maybe maybe maybe that
that's the right word in my vocabulary
to to to put it to put it together it's
harder right you don't have you you
don't have like that kind of like grace
period saying on this specific version
or whatever uh it's harder because
they're they're trying to say that what
we do is is targeting real world at the
real time the the second that the
exploit is being run the guy shows up at
the competition exploits Safari Chrome
Firefox Edge the same day the latest
version and and you can't disable over
the a update on a browser right gets
getting the update right at at exactly
the same second it just exploits all of
them that's like Elite as it gets as far
as I know yeah no it's it's insane and
it makes it makes sense too why you need
more time because for these for these
hacker one competitions we we are
attacking production environments as
well and they can submit patches and
stuff like that and sometimes that does
happen um but uh you know these are
these are hardened bug Bounty apps that
have been running a program for for a
long time um but the time frame is also
much shorter uh for us it's only like 10
to 14 days between when you get the
target to when are standing there
working you know in the environment so I
think one thing that's a little bit
tricky about this is in the hacker one
live hacking events you don't have as
much time to to craft these sort of um
masterpieces of exploits and there are
still people that do it for example shs
almost every event that he goes to shs
from the asset note team um almost every
single time he has like aone to own
crazy he's a crazy cor he is he almost
has a Pon to own you know level chain
rce at every single event you know that
that we go to I mean it's just it's
mindboggling and he does that in 10 to
14 days you know um from scratch he's
he's one of a kind like it is like he's
he's one of a kind and what he does is
is truly like remarkable I totally agree
and and and I think so yeah there's
definitely this aspect of like if you're
looking to be um if you're looking for
an environment of more collaboration and
stuff like that with with the team but
also I think with your with your um your
fellow competitors um hacker one has a
lot of uh places for that and
accommodations for that what does it
look like to collaborate with a team in
a Ponto own
environment uh with Ponto own usually uh
um you need to you need to understand
that um the money that you're going
after uh has a lot of has a lot of
conditions that you need to be you need
to be careful about if a Target yeah the
target uh has been put up on zdi on the
on the report list if you read the rules
carefully it says like 50,000 for this
target but is 50,000 for the first win
what does that mean exactly imagine uh
person a and person B and person C go to
the competition and they want to hack
this target if person a goes first they
do a random draw right they they
randomly put the put the names of people
in like a hat or some sort of wheel they
they they uh I don't know spin it and
then they take out the names and then um
let's say the order goes to I don't know
a b and c three three guys right three
people or whoever uh and then and then
and then they go on and then person a
manage to manages to exploit the device
successfully since he's the first guy or
she is the first guy um they get full
money for that
device they get the 50,000 then person B
goes person B can have three outcomes
kind of
three or four outcomes I I'll go over it
first they can have a unique Buck or
completely unique Buck chain they if
they do it and they they finish the
exploit so a full win it's called they
get 25,000 they get they don't get the
50,000 they get
25 even if it's a totally unique bug
just against that Target only get 25 not
the
5050 yeah they get 25 no they only get
25 only the first person so so so you
need the factor of luck that's one yeah
but uh I'll go I'll go over more detail
now so but the person now let's say the
person person B goes and the full win
25,000 the person C goes if it's a if
it's a full if it's completely new box
like so if they manage to find box that
the person a didn't find person B didn't
find and then person C is so special is
25,000 again but if it is duplicate with
those two other guys doesn't matter
which one of them they get half of the
half so they get half of the 25,000 so
12.5 if I'm not wrong yeah they get
12.5 that that's the money they get wow
that's very
different but there are some wiggle
rooms and some additional ideas to put
out there so each time uh for a Target
you have two things you have monetary
reward and master of paone points uh so
a Target is 50,000 it also has five
master of points master of paone points
uh so uh I just call them points now
because there's a lot of keys and I'll
mess up the sentence yeah so uh let's
say it has five points and uh 50,000
whatever if person a goes they get the
Five Points person B goes it's a unique
bug but there's a second person so they
get 25,000 but they do get the five
points and uh so if if if they worked so
hard to manage to find a lot of bugs but
they weren't so lucky to go first they
still might be able to be the master of
Pawn at the end day because the end day
they count the points who who whomever
has the highest points they get get to
be master of Pawn they get recognition
uh some sort of a trophy and some
additional money good money uh really
good money and um and uh oh so there's
some wiggle room here as well right so
imagine your person C right you're
nervous you go on you're like okay [__]
uh first person A and B win and then
this has got to be a dup right but for
some
reason uh that it says I don't know this
right there's like there's many ways to
Salvation or whatever know there there
are many ways to to do something right
so maybe for a bug maybe for a bug that
you managed to exploit you only needed
it to to chain two buxs maybe if I do it
I need to manage four things why it
depends uh but I will go through an
example with you to to make it more
established right but imagine you went
on your your your RC explo consists of
two bucks an information disclosure and
maybe a arbitrary file upload whatever
right maybe you needed to disclose the
file system path in order to be able to
write to a specific directory so you
need it and the the fall path is random
so you need to disclose It Whatever
right so you need to change these two
two things together so your final explo
consists of two bucks right but imagine
person person Tre goes right uh so and
so these two bugs were for person Tre
person C is let's call it but person a
managed to I don't know use only one bug
to get the RC right they didn't need the
information disclosure right when person
SE
go since they have two bucks and it's an
additional that the person a didn't have
so it's like a paral d that adds to your
money that it's a partial dupe exactly
it's a partial dupe so it adds to your
money it's based on some sort of a
percentage but it's not half of the half
anymore it's like some sort of a
onethird or like I don't know inter
interesting so more complex chains or or
chains that have more components to them
get rewarded
further the more complex if you can make
it the better it is there so that's kind
of the way to look at insanely different
from the live hacking events because so
much rules so much rules rules in the
hacker one live hacking events you only
get a dup if it's literally the exact
same bug you know I mean or if it's on
the same end point or whatever right um
so if I get an rce via you know um you
know pseudo random number generator plus
a file upload right something like that
and you get an RC via SQL injection to
file right to you know that sort of
thing a different endpoint both of those
get the full Bounty um however if you if
you know people submit the same thing
then the the same prize for that that
critical bug or whatever starts getting
split you know in half in thirds and
fourths right um so that's that's very
different and actually the way that that
zdi does it um is very for a second I
thought it was it was better for the
researcher because it gets it gets
halfed and then halfed but it's
actually that that Target in general
right so once the first person claims
the first 50k Prize or whatever for that
Target the most that the the researcher
B and researcher C are competing for is
25 Grand is that accurate exactly you
got it right you got it right man so
it's so much luck that draw is worth 25
Grand to so much luck man so many
factors I told you it's like combat I
told you it's yeah yeah um it is
and U lot lot of things you need to like
the vendor doesn't push a patch you're
lucky you're
you fin it and you have three attempts
and each attempt is minutes so you need
to be careful with your everything you
need to I've kind of wrote down like the
steps that you need to go through for a
Target I can read it for you right just
like a quickly Yeah so basically with a
Target uh before before I read this uh
I've I've lot of this is based on
another talk that Alex plet Alex plaset
is a phenomenal security researcher who
works at NCC group
Alex plaset if if I'm not pronouncing
him pronouncing his name right wrong
he's a phenomenal security researcher
he's he's crazy how good he is he's been
exploiting everything that you can think
of from the back in the ancient time
until now and way more I'm sure in the
future uh he's a good friend of mine and
then he has given another kind of like a
interview talk about Pon toon uh with a
uh in another YouTube channel or
something that I forgot the name for I
apologize for it uh this is my bad I
maybe I give you the link you put it
down there or like put it in a link or
something so people can go it's a it's a
great YouTube channel a great
interviewer and great interviewee I
think I don't know great people in
general right um so Alex has kind of
like put together like a uh kind of like
a list methodology of how how things go
go together when looking at targets and
I'm trying to like replicate the same
thing that he said so basically because
I I exactly do his method and then once
he so I sorry uh no you're good get I
should have actually told you before the
podcast to get some some water or
something like that because you see let
me get some water during this whole
thing I've been like drinking my coffee
or whatever do do you have water nearby
or you got to go grab it yeah it's let
let me go grab a second hey guys real
quick I just wanted to give a shout to
the hacker content team they have been
absolutely killing it the past couple
months taking the content from the
podcast and condensing it down into
consumable social media posts whether it
be shorts or text posts or whatever
they've been rocking it so uh I just
wanted to give them a shout out and let
you know that they do all sorts of
cybercity content as well as social
media management they do technical blogs
they do uh comprehensive social media
management uh so if your organization
could benefit from any of those types of
services make sure you head over to
hacker content.com drop them a line and
mention the podcast when you do to get
your first month of cyber security
content marketing services for free all
right that's it let's get back to the
pond all right all right all right so
we're gonna let this man get some water
really quick okay so tell us about this
the steps for
pontoon yeah so there steps for pontoon
inspired by Alex blasket uh what it says
is uh basically you first you do
background research right you have this
target that they announc for p toon I
don't know it's it's I don't know router
or smart speaker whatever you do a
background research right you look for
you start searching for the product to
see if there were any previous
vulnerabilities previous write ups
previous ways to get an initial shell
all of that could be important and
valuable to you previous reverse
engineerings and mitigation bypasses
stuff you learn all of that right so
it's better to build up on other
researchers that are out there instead
of starting from scratch so sometimes
you need to so because only some of the
targets from pwn two may may got repeat
may get repeated not all of them right
so it's it's always best to do some
background research uh go through the uh
previous vulnerabilities and all that
and then after that I'm just reading
reading through it um then you need to
get the device get a shell on it
basically some sort of a way to debug it
and all that uh to research it to put it
in a like a lab environment and then you
start after you got a shell or whatever
you start uh mapping the attack surfaces
what's available what can be exploited
what's important what's excluded all
that after that you start doing revers
engineering static analysis code review
whatever it is fuzzing basically looking
for bugs and sometimes you need to as
you go for different kind of targets
sometimes you need to make your make
your own tools for that Target maybe
there's some sort of a tedious task
maybe maybe there is some sort of a
condition with this target that you need
to make a tool for so you need to be you
need to be fast agile about like writing
plugins for I don't know like your
favorite disassembler there is grra
whatever
uh write something about it uh for it uh
and then you have the after you I don't
know found the box through fuzzing code
review Dynamic static whatever you did
kind of magic then you get to exploit
development where you make your PC and
then one thing that is really important
is making your exploit as efficient as
possible as reliable as possible and as
portable as possible because the day of
the competition the POC Gods will [__]
with you the way that you can think
of uh your your your your cable goes
missing or your cable who that you were
using for five years without any problem
starts don't not working or this device
doesn't work or the battery keeps dying
or the system gets giving you a blue
screen or a kernel panic or whatever I
don't know like or your like uh USBC Hub
doesn't work or the the the libraries
the the libraries that you're importing
your exploit don't work and then okay
you need to okay this happens now you
need to move your exploit to a different
machine maybe ZD gives you a new laptop
saying okay launch through launch from
this laptop so you need to have your
exploit ready uh even even your laptop
got I don't know burned or crashed or
exploded you you have the explode
somewhere else that you can get it uh
somewhere secure hopefully and then uh
you can put put it quickly on another
machine with no setup previous ly and
the exploit can be launched quickly
without problem and you need to be able
to write your exploit as beautiful as
possible because this happened to me
right so um one time that I was doing
the competition um at a certain point um
I I've got my exploit ready it was like
a full chain it was a memory corruption
when and it was relying on a Rob chain
that uh was was like pulling off a r
chain and when I uh when I cut my FL and
then uh landed in Toronto in um Canada
and I went to the competition and I it
was my turn to to exploit the device um
one of the devices uh when it got to my
turn I realized that the vendor had just
patched as just push the patch uh it
wasn't even a security patch it was just
like a feature patch and I think they
did that purposely to because they knew
there might be like memory Corruptions
it's not really farfetched for a vendor
to think that
and then they push like a feature patch
that was just adding some sort of a
string or something uh that would just
like cause the the the main executable
on that device to have like different
offsets and then uh that kind of like uh
that kind of led into my rapin not
working properly but since I knew uh
from hearing out past experiences from
other people at the competition that
it's best to make a exploit like refine
and like make a clean exploit that would
be portable and would be easily
modifiable on stage at that moment when
when it's your turn it you've already
had a failed attempt and you have couple
of minutes to complete it and you've put
months of work uh to to get something
out of it it's like it's like an
investment and then you don't want
things to go wrong so you need to like
keep it together and then do the changes
which I would and especially like shout
out to zdi when you're at this stage
when you're on stage and you're you're
doing your exploitation they're super
they're super uh like calm and trying to
help and try to even they ask you like
what do you need what's wrong can we do
anything tell us the problem may maybe
we can do something maybe we can maybe
we can change something like they always
try to like come up with a way to to
help you they they love to buy the bugs
they love to pay pay the researchers
because they know it's so much more and
uh that that's that's what really good
that's what's really good about them and
then long story short since the exploit
was was well written this I I can kind
of say I I I managed to change what I
needed to change without breaking lot of
parts in the exploit which was
exploiting a race condition and a memory
corruption at the same time wow and then
got it working and then it landed on the
second attempt I think uh and I was
super happy uh uh and then I got through
and then that was lesson to me the
relief in that moment must be crazy and
and um yeah well props to you for
building out a cool exploit and I I do
have a similar story to this where um
you know we only have two weeks before
the live hacking events to actually do
any of this stuff so this one time I was
really working hard on a hardware device
and I was going down this rabbit hole
and I knew that it was possible to uh
get a very impactful I I'll just say you
know we were able to take over this
whole device and look through the camera
and look through the microphone right um
and listen through the microphone
remotely and um and I was like I I was
like I know that this is possible but we
didn't have enough time and I popped it
less than an hour before the end of the
PO the competition you know in that two
period up to that last hour and man the
whole team was sitting behind me and I
like showed it and they're like yeah you
got it and I was like wow yes you know
like it's just the best ever so I think
there's a lot of stress that comes along
that you know but there's also a lot of
payoff
right yeah yeah exactly um it it it has
a it has a really good payoff right as I
said earlier right at the beginning uh I
didn't know at at some point that even
there there's going to be jobs for it or
there is a job for it uh it's just the
feeling the excitement right uh of
course I'm working for money right uh
just like nowadays but when I started it
it was just just like the only purpose
was was the feeling and the feeling only
and then the excitement like I I can't
find it in anything else personally
personally I didn't find it in anything
else so
far yeah now that's amazing man okay so
so you said you know in this list from
Alex um you know you've got create a a
very high integrity um easily portable
you know you've got all the um libraries
and stuff you need packaged together
you've got all of your office sets in
variables rather than just like you know
add it into Strings or whatever right so
for easy modification you got your
exploit ready to go what's the next step
in the
process yeah so uh as I said I went
through a lot of steps but uh after the
after you know like your exploit is like
proper and then uh it's easily portable
you just one other thing that these
might sound the same thing but even
though they're kind of like Collide but
testing your exploit again and again and
again not going to lie if if the device
is not expensive I'll I'll sometimes buy
another device just a fresh one I just
plug it in and run the Expo just just
plug it in I don't do anything else
because it might surprise you but
sometimes like sometimes like weird
things happen like the first time that
you visit the device there is the Ajax
call on the HTTP request that's sets the
time zone of the device without you
knowing it and right at this on stage
the the zdi device is fresh out of the
box and maybe they didn't visit the
first page and then your exploit is
failing and you're like why is it
failing and maybe it's because well just
because nobody has ever visited this
certain page which normally specific
example yes it's like very weird stuff
that's crazy man that's great H crazy
crazy stuff yeah yeah one thing I think
uh from before uh I kind of like did an
example about when you have bugs with
like which is like a chain of multiple
stuff and then the more complex the bug
is the better because then when you dup
you don't fully dup you do like a
partial dupe uh one other thing is like
another example will be imagine you're
exploiting a memory corruption and then
uh when you're exploiting it uh
did did this actually happened in one of
the recent competitions that I went to
uh for some reason uh when I was doing
the memor corruption I've managed to I
managed to pull it off to the memor
corruption without the need to find the
in information disclosure and leaked any
addresses from a like to defeat aslr
because I was like right in my R chain I
was relying on some addresses which
weren't getting randomized but one of
the team was clever enough that thought
okay let's instead make our exploit
harder and we find an info leak and add
it to our chain even though they didn't
need to but they just made their exploit
more difficult because they thought okay
if they did like a random draw and then
we didn't go first and then we went
second or third at least our our explo
is more complex so we don't do like a
full dup a partial dup at least which is
which is smart and ZD actually Tech
encourages you to do so
yeah wow very cool
I think I think those sort of things are
exactly what we want to know about going
into these competitions right having
that sort of metag gaming aspect how do
you how do you um play the environment
properly so that you can maximize your
return um so that's that's really
helpful stuff um okay man I think I've
got a picture right I think I've got a
picture of what it looks like to do um
uh pwn to own a little bit more um the
last the only thing other thing that I
wanted to talk about was uh the pwn or
the master of pone title right so um in
a in a pwn to own environment is there
there's just one winner you know
everybody who has a successful exploit
is considered a winner of of Pon to own
or whatever and then there's one person
that comes out as the master of of paone
um is there is there any awards for like
second or third or fourth place or is it
just that one master pone
title yeah so people go to Pontoon they
are I think the senten is maybe I'm
doing the grammar right or wrong uh they
are a winner at Ponto not winner of the
ponon right so they're not winning whole
thing but they're just they're just one
of the one of the many winners at ponon
right and then there sometimes there's
this like uh crazy Geniuses who who
manage to win Pontoon and then the whole
thing and then they will be nominated as
master of Pawn uh who's can be only one
there is no second place no third place
it's just one place and then wow they
get a statue reward like a trophy which
is always different uh either is like a
I don't know a signed basketball in like
a cool cage or like a statue of a of a
of a beetle of a bug or something or
something which is just like a token of
appreciation and also a certain amount
of money and also I think uh let me let
me just make sure uh uh that I'm saying
this right uh um so with with ZD you
have something called a status which is
uh so so a lot of people know but ZD zdi
purchases purchases boxs U and when they
purchase these boxs you get some points
uh like I think it's I think it's
similar to like signal or whatever in
hacker one um I think so but they call
it like yeah exactly so you you got like
points you got you got you got status
you gather points and then you reach a
status with this point points for
example 15,000 points uh will get you a
bronze status and then 25,000 points is
silver and then it's gold and it's
Platinum uh which is the maximum status
that you can have and when you win pwn
toon as a master of Pawn when you win
the whole thing uh you instantly get a
platinum status on your account and
these statuses what they do is basically
yeah exactly what they do is they um
whenever you submit a book to zdi and
then these the researchers will like
review it produce it make sure it's
legit and all of that and then it's cool
when they want to purchase it based on
your status they do a multiplication on
the amount of money they're going to
give you uh uh that uh so if you're like
Platinum maybe you get double of the
money if if you were supposed to get
five grand for a RC on on a product you
get like 10 grand right based on the
status that you have on on the zdi zdi
platform uh yeah that's pretty much it
and also so uh when I said the the more
complex the bo box is in the chain you
get like partial dup and that's like a
technique to use it's because don't
don't forget CDA is buying the bug and
also is buying your Technique so if you
made your exploit more complex to adding
more block chains to it it's good for
them as well because you're giving them
more techniques to learn about um so
selling more techniques yeah that's it's
very cool that they've found this a a
profitable business model with their
with their um you know product
essentially the result of this funds
enough you know sales um to make it
worth it for them to pay out all these
researchers I I I I think that's really
cool um in in the hacker one en how this
works a little bit differently oh go
ahead go ahead sorry I bad habit jumping
in people's talking no I want to hear
that I want to hear that tell me
that okay do you know how how Pon
started no no I don't okay uh so
uh with with pwn 2 and the way it
started as far as as far as I know at
canc West which is a security conference
in Vancouver Canada um back in the day
uh I I don't remember the exact date
maybe 2016 or 17 or maybe 15 I don't
know one of those uh times uh U zdi was
a still like purchasing box and zdi was
a thing and then uh can seest organizer
asked the crowd that uh back in the time
people were like always saying like
MacBook is the securest or whatever and
then uh they've asked if any anyone from
the audience can hack a Macbook remotely
remote code execution and if they do if
they pone it they can own it and then
they asked so zdi was was there as sale
as well I think as an sponsor or
something and then they asked zdi if zdi
is willing to purchase the BG and zdi
says said yes we we purchase it for
10,000 if anyone can do it and then
somebody actually did they they found
theability in MacBook like it's crazy at
the time they they found a RC in MacBook
quick time and then they exploited
remotely and then uh ponon kind of
started From There initially it was only
browsers they were only like doing like
I don't know like Safari Chrome uh
Internet Explorer at the time and then
uh after that uh it kind of like evolved
into a lot of more devices
virtualizations VMware virtual box uh
like Enterprise Solutions SharePoint
exchange and the Microsoft teams and
then it kind of evolved into uh mobile
devices which is like uh Samsung Sony
xiaomi Apple Google um and then like
Enterprise Solutions like uh iot devices
Smart Home Speakers printers and then
also and then after that it was like IC
products which is like SCA products like
right you know like critical uh critical
Solutions and then after that it it
evolved into Automotive which is the
newest type of thing uh which is like
infotainment systems smart EV Chargers
and all that and zdi started from paying
hundreds of thousands like like 300,000
400,000 total at one competition to now
paying over millions now like they like
they pay like at a single competition
they pay over a million now and then
which is crazy so the competition is
way way more now it's it's much more uh
and there's there's a sad truth to to
one other thing as well is back in the
day it was either solo researchers or uh
Team of like two three people just like
solo people now people are competing who
are coming from companies like company
sponsor teams who have like I don't know
40 50 employee at the company and
they're paying the paying the employees
salary uh so no limit on that to work on
these products so crazy like if if a
solo research is working on it they're
not getting paid until they find the
bike right but imagine you work for a
company who's paying your salary so you
know like if you're going to look at it
like 825 825 you're going to get your
salary at the end of the month so so you
have that calmness you don't you don't
have any stress on it and then uh right
those people will will like 20 people
come to the competition right so and
then you're not competing against a team
of two or three you're competing against
a company of 20 people and they're doing
it to get PR which which makes sense
kind of but I'm just I'm just saying it
putting it out there
even though it is it is a wellknown
thing but for anyone who doesn't know
things get more difficult when you're
competing against a company who has so
so imagine if if when I'm competing I'm
I'm re I'm I'm breaking the hardware
attacking the hardware reversing uh
fuzzing U writing the exploit myself
when that company is doing it they have
five experts who only understand
Hardware since they were a little kid
they were designing pcbs and and then
just like just building like Hardware
right so they give the device to there
so the initial stage was getting a shell
on the device right they get a shell on
the device in two hours because they're
five seasoned Hardware like experts they
get it in two hours and then they pass
it on to the next Department who are
like experts in writing fuzzers they
write the fuzzers they pass it on to the
next apartment meantime like they're
they're working on different time zones
247 the research has never stopped never
paused and they go and then people like
me or someone else show up a solo guy a
oneman army Twan Army three man army
show up and U they're competing against
these teams right which is crazy that is
crazy that's people should know crazy
it's hard yeah yeah wow dude well I it
seems like the competition has evolved a
lot over the years and uh you know
hopefully we'll see some accommodations
for you know researchers that are going
at it more more single-handedly versus
these these big teams but also you know
um as the game changes approaches to the
game has to change and we've seen that
in the heck one bugani world as well um
you know just trying to to build
collaboration um units essentially uh
and and also you know building
automation out to try to help with these
sort of things and but that also
highlights one of the main differences
between the zdi competitions and the
hacker One World which is this is
probably the biggest difference is zdi
only pays for remote code execution and
you know at a hacker one event you know
there's normally two three four five um
you know remote Cod executions but uh
there's like 700 other vs you know um
and and so uh once again when talking
about the differences between these two
worlds um the fact that we're able to
pay the bills with our little sea surfs
in our in our xsss and our idors um
while working on these more complex
exploits really I think makes it
sustainable in the long term for for us
to be able to continue to do bug Bounty
um whereas like you said before zdi
Ponto competitions it's like hard mode
right you got to go in there who knows
if if you know the the the wheel stops
on doesn't stop on your number then
there goes your your car you know like
and and there's a lot more volatility to
the process and uh and then also the
exploits accepted are much more um are
much more have to be much more technical
have to be much more um RC oriented than
than maybe even business logic oriented
or or impact to the actual uh Target
ecosystem Sy oriented um so very very
interesting to see those differences
there yeah and uh there are some people
they're like so at the last P that was
held in Vancouver when I said like these
like exactly this like R SE only and
then uh the difficulty of competing
against these companies is um this guy
whose name is Manfred Paul um I don't
know if you know him but he he he came
in one guy exploited all the browsers Ed
Safari Firefox Chrome all of them all of
them exploited by one guy and he he's
this crazy dude and he won the
competition like a lot of companies were
there I'm not naming names but lot of
companies were there and then he managed
to win it he and he's exceptionally
talented we're talking about someone who
who Who's like I think is out of this
world I don't know like
exactly he he he he he's I I I'm not I
can't even like analyze him to put them
in into words like it's crazy but um
yeah with with Ponto hard mode is RC uh
lot of lot of factors like luck and a
lot of other stuff but it's it's it's an
elite competition and I know people who
are only doing it to prove a prove to
themselves and challenge themselves to
do it and mainly compared to the money
part uh but I think that's if I were do
it if I were to do it and I think I will
someday I think that would be the reason
it's it's not as because these
incentives are good but more so like I
would I would rather I would I would
like to compete in it I would like to be
um you know just going back to the
hacker One World um you know the master
of paone for hacker one is the um is the
the mvh the most valuable hacker and
when you win you get these these belts
I'll point to them you know back here
these belts yeah yeah yeah and I I uh
you know I I've got those and I I would
like to also conquer the world of uh of
pone to own but man you know when you're
up against people like this this guy
that rolls in here this Manfred dude
that that rolls in there and just
demolishes all browsers in one in one
attempt it's like wow uh that's
definitely going to be a challenge to go
up against and and I I just can't
imagine you know yeah I I just can't
believe there's not more incentive there
and because this is so such a
challenging thing that people are doing
um I do want to get your take on on one
more thing before we wrap up which is um
yeah do you think that zdi should in the
pontone competition should accept bugs
that are not uh
RC in the future uh to compete with the
other bug Bounty Arena um because
obviously you know there are some
situations where it's like oh I've got
full off bypass but I I don't have a way
to turn this into rce there's just no
way to turn it into rce in this front
end of the system you know or whatever
there's lots of impactful bugs that are
out there that will just destroy a
product but um these are not being paid
for uh from from in these competitions
what are your what are your thoughts on
that uh yeah so
zdi well uh let's let's let's look at it
this way right um again it's their rules
and it's not it's not really up to me
thinking like what what should they what
should they or shouldn't they do but uh
um for some devices like uh mobile
phones things that like make sense like
with mobile things I think they have
like exceptions saying that if if it's a
mobile phone we allow connecting USB
like a like a USB something because lot
of there's a lot of stuff going on under
over like the lightning protocol that
the cable and iPhone uses like lot of
like lot of lot of protocols go on there
lot of people have found memory
Corruptions uh like it is accepted on
those or or like for example on mobile
devices um like phones like Samsung
xiaomi whatever they allow one click
exploit as well so basically you share a
link and then when they click on the
link okay so it's like so and they do
that and they also when you have like a
when you go to the go to the competition
and you have a valid exploit but you're
not able to finish the exploit on stage
but it is an actual valid exploit they
also give you some percent they they
offer you offer to you that they will
still buy it from you if you want to but
for a small percentage just to just so
you don't feel like You' wasted your
whole time it is not the same price as
you could have get uh but you you
couldn't finish the book and this is
just like a token of appreciation again
for the researcher too saying they can
what numbers look like on that like are
they like half are they like 10% are
they
like I I I don't have it in my mind I
think it's different every time uh it
really depends gotcha yeah okay that
makes sense all right man um I'm looking
through this document here
um yeah I think I think we've covered
most of the stuff that I wanted to cover
with regards to pwn to own and what the
experience is like and and your approach
to hacking and that sort of thing the
the only other thing that I think we've
got time for is I would like to have
gone through some of the bugs that
you've uh reported recently um but I'll
just ask you one question about the um
the what's up gold preo rce um yeah and
that you that you've blogged about on
your on your website summoning do team
um in this exploit you know there's
there's a lot of um technical
explanation where you're going through
the the code and I love how you know you
show the trace of where you know what
function calls what and create that
little graph and that sort of thing
that's super helpful for understanding
all of this um I'm wondering so this is
utilizing the uh WCF
uh protocol right within within this net
environment um and that's right so this
is a this is a TCP based service is that
is that accurate uh let me see here or
was that the other one that yeah yeah
yeah yeah so so the thing is uh so uh we
have something called WCF Windows
communication Foundation it's super easy
to understand the way that you could put
it is Imagine RPC right if if if yeah
it's it's RPC right you're remotely
calling procedures you're remotely
calling methods right they expose some
sort of methods under code that you can
call those methods remotely and then in
order for this call to happen it needs
to go through a custom protocol there
used to be do remoting which was very
very vulnerable and they replicated it
and introduce WCF which is this one so w
WCF is like an alternative to net
remoting for this sub exactly this is
XML based it seems um and and so depends
depend so you can yeah you you can
configure your double CF to use
different kind of like they call it like
uh like different kind of bindings so
you can have like HTTP binding or TCP
binding and like there's there's there
is way more bindings but they basically
what what these bindings mean mean is
like do you want it to be sent over HTTP
or TCP and if you choose HTTP it most of
the times it goes through as like a soap
soap protocol which is made by Microsoft
itself so you don't you don't write the
soap Microsoft takes care of itself for
you they they make your calls into like
soap formatted things or you use the TCP
way I mean like they call it TCP but
everything is like all of it's basically
over TCP but the TCP binding what it
does is it it's another custom protocol
which you're sending like some sort of
like encoded btes and stuff like that
like
a size like a size field bit field like
a structure and all of that like a like
a like a protocol and then you send it
across which is also taken care of by
Microsoft but writing the nextro wise
when you're dealing with like a a
binding which is HTTP at at the end you
can like write some sort of a python
code to send like a HTTP request over
and get it done with but if you're
exploiting a TCP based binding you need
to write like a C client which was the
other blog that I published which was a
C client code to write the exploits
gotcha okay okay so um that that that
all makes sense that cleared it up it's
a way to do RPC um a a newer version of
moding it could be over TP it could be
over HTTP or soap or whatever just
depending on what finding is being used
um and and I'm wondering um so when
we're looking at these sort of obviously
your your thing is net and and you're
you're really good at that um uh what
what is the what is how often are you
seeing stuff in WCF versus just like a
normal uh HTP you know IIs or whatever
environment um and is this potentially
an environment that uh researchers might
be sort of sleeping on within within a
lot of Enterprise applications or iot
devices or
whatever yeah so with uh with with uh
WCF I really recommend people to to look
at it it's not something new that I've
been doing I've been doing it for years
and years and I've been submitting like
bugs about WCF a lot of times it's just
something that uh like people don't tend
to blog about maybe about this so it
keeps being like a little bit um not as
well known even though if you Google
about like w of exploitation you will
see blogs going back to like four years
from now that we're talking or maybe
three years from now like maybe maybe
from like 2020 or 2019 even uh people
have exploited it people have given
talks about it people have written blog
posts about it uh presentations and
everything but you don't see it being
blogged about publicly a lot of
times as much as it might could it could
be might could have been um but yeah I
really recommend people to to to
um basically start understanding what
WCF is start writing like some some sort
of a custom lab environment and stuff
build it up and then try to like
experiment with it understand it exploit
it and all of that and then uh which
which we also do in our course by the
way covered in the course yeah yeah yeah
so in the course there's there's like
every like I can I can bravely say like
80% of any kind of remote technology in
net that can happen any kind of like RPC
WCF remoting or lot of other things that
I don't want to name now because I want
to like keep it as like the secret sauce
in the course sure I cover them all and
how to exploit them and how to audit
them and how to write exploit clients
for him and all that uh but yeah uh it's
WCF is worth investigating and work
worth working on yeah very cool I like
that a lot um and and just one last
question on that so um yeah you know
this one is the one in the blog that I'm
looking at right now is listening on
Port 9642 and 9643
um if we see those those I ass that is
specific to this application this isn't
on every single you WC so when we're
looking for WCF services are we trying
to track down this uh like in this
example it says nma api. exe doc config
so is there normally like aex Doc config
file that we can look at to see where
the the various routing is occurring and
what kind of bindings are being
registered good question so when you're
auditing WCF you're dealing with three
things address binding contract based on
the Microsoft documentation you're
dealing with these three things right uh
you need to find the address The Binding
and the contract these are the three
things the address is the address like
SNM API whatever right The Binding is
the type of binding that you're going to
be talking to http TCP and many others
there is not just just those two and
then contract is actually the code the
methods that you want to invoke so um
when you want to exploit it you need to
find all or you need to find or you need
to write the interface for those
contracts a contract is basically the
methods that the that the target server
is offering to you that you you can
invoke so you need to build it up and
after you build these tree up at this
point in contract you need to if you
work on it and like just like read the
blog and like Google around maybe you
can get to it hi that you can like
stickly these together and then finish
the exploit but the the the thing is uh
with it is the question that you ask
okay how can we now find this tree uh so
it's not always a config file it can
even be in the code so there can be
there can be no config B at all no conf
file at all you need to be also a
exactly you need to be able to decompile
and look for a WCF setup and
registration and those addresses and
binding and contracts in The Code by DEC
compiling it with like the inspire
whatever the compil you want to use
always conf file what are some some
keywords we should be looking at for
that like for example I see in here
basic HTP binding something like that if
we search exactly the word binding the
word binding itself will give it out
binding perfect love that so so then
that'll help us track down our sources
right these are services that are being
um exposed and then we can sort of track
the through the syns and that actually
makes me think of one more question I
wanted to ask you there's a big debate
on the podcast um you know I think it
this is mostly um occurs when we have
targets that we're looking at that
doesn't have a massive codebase because
if you have a massive code base you have
to address things a little bit
differently but um do you normally start
with sources or syncs and when you're
doing a source code uh analysis like are
you normally looking at like um you know
all right this is how there's like eight
Services here and I'm going to go
through every single function for every
single service or do you look for
vulnerable code patterns and then work
it back up to a a
source
um Let me let me put it this way right
this uh again I don't I don't I don't
represent any like like I don't know one
researchers whatever this is just this
is just me as a single person who's
answering this right um if you look at
the the the basic answer is I do all of
them but let let me elaborate a little
bit um if he if start with sinks and
then work our way back to sources like
find dangerous things and then find out
how can we hit them how can we reach
them that's
good why bad like if if it was bad it
wasn't a method it is it is good I use
it to this day as well but don't limit
yourself to only that as well sometimes
following sources to syn like sometimes
just like following sources doesn't
matter it doesn't matter if you think
they're going to hit a snc or not just
following the sources that's just
following them see what the heck is the
application is going to do with this
that I'm going to be providing to you
because sometimes if you only look for
the syns uh sometimes there might be
some sort of a logical bug which which
isn't relying on a well-known sync or or
a sync that you might say but a kind of
behavior that is dangerous to this
certain application right so it's always
good to also follow the things follow
follow the sources doesn't matter if you
know indeed that it's going to be
hitting a syn so both of them syn to s s
syn that's wolf good and that's what a
lot of my personal friends do the same
thing too yeah yeah I think I think
that's what we all do I think I think um
you know it also depends if you see a
bunch of really obvious stuff you might
jump right into the sinks and try to
trace your way back but what I always
say is if you spend time on sources
you're never going to like regret that
time because it's time that you're going
to understand more about that
application spend understanding
appliation you know and um and
understanding
how the application flows um and you're
going to get a better feel intuitively
for that app that will help you trace
back up from the sources as well I mean
from the SS as well does that make sense
am I representing that correctly that
you got it right on the point Perfect
all right man wow um well this has been
a long episode and uh a great one one of
my favorites so far for sure um I would
love to have you come back on again
sometime and discuss um a little bit
more of these nitty-gritty details about
net and you know oh we're getting in
here um you know we're checking out WCF
services that sort of thing so we'll
have to set that up again in the future
but um uh for now man uh Cena thank you
so much for coming on and anything you
want to shout out before we end the
podcast uh yeah of course uh thank you
very much first of all let me take you
that take you take you up on that offer
uh whenever uh whenever you you feel
like please give me give me like a give
me a ping give me a shout out and then
I'll show up we can do like a session I
share my screen or whatever and we
exploited doet vulnerability I don't
know we exploit a Exchange Server I
server we exploited tricky net based
targets or whatever um I'm happy to do
so uh did did you you you've guys buil
up a great platform and I like to
contribute to it because I know it has a
good Spotlight on it and uh it helps me
and you at the same time I think uh so I
appreciate I appreciate that you having
me here that's
first uh second one is I just wanted to
give a few shout outs to some people who
who who who' helped me a lot and then um
I I remember the name U i' I've tried to
write them in a note so you're going to
be looking at me and thinking that I'm
I'm reading reading from something and
that's right uh let me let me just uh
let me just bring it up um yeah so I
just first I want to give a shout out to
uh to the zero initiative uh zdi uh like
um they have been always supportive of
my work and
like help me to to get into the
competition and show up especially Brian
gorens as I said who's the vice
president of thread research at Trad
micro and also Dustin Charles who's the
head of tread awareness these are like
two lovely folks who were like always
always helping me through ponon and just
like making making the dream happen
basically next I want to thank uh
Michael Michael the plant he's a he's
actually a zdi employee he's a research
arer and uh he's such a great guy he he
sometimes he he he runs my attempts on
on pwn to own and then uh when he runs
him he's always like he's he's a calm
person and helps me to run my attempts
really good so shout out to him as well
H I want to give a shout out to
uh shout out sorry I want to give a
shout out to radic and uh radic from
flashback team uh I don't know if you
know him uh he and Pedro rero both of
them Brad and Pedro shout out to both of
you uh they're both great people they
have a hardware Hardware exploitation
training that you can go to um the these
two these two guys uh Pedro and radic um
I think the only reason that I got into
Hardware exploitation was because of
these people I personally never took
their trading but I I know for a fact
that their training is phenomenal and i'
I've only learned uh I've only learned
my starter net exploit sorry Hardware
exploitation I talked about a lot about
net but my Hardware exploitation from
their public research and public blog
post and they were the reason that I got
into Hardware expectation I want to give
a give a shout out to my dear friend
surush surush Dal he's he's what like
he's always been Idol to me what a
legend he's one of my best friends like
he has I can say like everything that I
know about net is because of him and
that's it like it's because of him like
I shouldn't be honestly I shouldn't be I
shouldn't have a d and exportation
training he should have it but for some
reason uh I don't know the Up Up Is Down
something I don't know the night you
know all of like reverse everything and
then uh I'm doing the training um and
also step silly Mr me
he he's he's the only reason that I've
got into one research I just like I've
been trying to follow his his footsteps
and everything and uh he he's all I
still haven't reached this level but I'm
seeing that I'm I'm stepping on the
right path and another shout out to two
other people and I will promise you I'm
done chy p uh chy works at uh Trend
Micro as well he he always does
phenomenal doet research andet
exploitation and he's always a
inspiration to my training to my
exploits to everything. net that I do
he's always an inspiration to my work I
I get inspired so much from his work and
also orang s for basically like Shifting
the whole infos like concept to like
another level like he always like brings
up with with crazy other stuff there's a
lot of other people who I've who who who
are here that I like to give a shout out
but these were all them and one other
person and lastly is is the guy that I
who I said at the at the beginning uh
mean M he he was he was a mentor a
teacher a friend to me and he's always
be and uh I've learned a ton from him
and maybe if it wasn't because of him I
wouldn't be doing infoi at all wow man
that's it sorry a long list that was uh
that was legendary I think one of the
things about you that I've gotten the
impression from from this is that you
are very grateful and you're very humble
and even just in times when we're off
camera during this podcast like you've
always been very accommodating and
you've been very grateful that you're
that you know you're able to be here and
I feel you know I feel like it's vice
versa man I feel like I'm so lucky to
have you on the podcast and get your
your um your takes on all this stuff so
um that's the best situation right where
we're both grateful and happy and uh
pleased to have each other so um thank
you so much for coming on man and and I
just wanted to say uh of that list uh
suou obviously a legend but uh chy p uh
same for orange but chy PB is someone
that just came on my radar recently with
this SharePoint XX that came out and um
I actually had a note in this episode to
talk about uh his research on the
SharePoint xxe because um he he Echoes
something that you mentioned as well
with with the um the debugger being so
important which is that you can validate
your assumptions instead of guessing and
in his research he um he he exploits an
processing was disabled yeah exactly
that's exactly it man the DTD processing
was disabled and the XML resolver was
set to a bunch of different stuff and is
like wow why would you even try xxc when
you see this and I think it's because
you have more introspection into the
environment and see what's actually
going on so debugger um yeah is
definitely on my uh on my on my tweet
mention on my like tweet notifications
on list now um so yeah his name is by
the way sorry by the way uh when I when
I said these people's names uh maybe I I
used their handle or something ch's ch's
name is peer uh Ju Just want to just
want to say it and uh sorry for the for
the long list uh I I don't get a lot of
I don't get a lot of chance to to be on
something that will be seen or heard by
people and when I am uh I've got to give
give shout out to these people because
if was wasn't because of them I wouldn't
be here honestly and thank you so much
for having me here of course dude of
course man that gratitude it it warms
the heart and and for anybody you know
that's listening that's thinking wow
that was a long list hey now you got a
list to go and look at and people to
follow and research look into because
those are the people that have made uh
Cena who he is you know and and you know
clearly they've got a lot to offer the
world so um all right thank you so much
man great
podcast and that's a wrap on this
episode of critical thinking thanks so
much for listening and if you want more
critical thinking content head over to
ctbb show/ Discord join the Discord
there's lots of great conversations and
chats going on over there and if you
want to support the show there's the
Discord subscriber tiers which give you
access to master classes amas hack Longs
exclusive scripts and an exclusive chat
Channel with us we'll see you there